. ALL RIGHT.
GOOD AFTERNOON EVERYBODY AND WELCOME TO THE JUNE 3RD,
2025 REGULAR MEETING OF THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL?
>> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN PRESENT
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN PRESENT SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY
PRESENT SUPERVISOR ENGARDIO AND ENGARDIO PRESENT SUPERVISOR
FOR FIELDER FIELDER PRESENT SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD
PRESENT SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN PRESIDENT MANDOLIN PRESENT
SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR PRESENT SUPERVISOR SADR SADR
PRESENT SUPERVISOR CHERYL SHERYL PRESENT AND SUPERVISOR
WALTON WILSON PRESENT MR. PRESIDENT ALL MEMBERS ARE
PRESENT. >> THANK YOU.
THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS ACKNOWLEDGES THAT
WE ARE ON THE UNCEDED ANCESTRAL HOMELAND OF THE ROMITA COLONY
WHO ARE THE ORIGINAL INHABITANTS OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO PENINSULA AS THE INDIGENOUS STEWARDS OF THIS
LAND AND IN ACCORDANCE WITH THEIR TRADITIONS PARAMETERS
SHALL HAVE NEVER CEDED LOST NOR FORGOTTEN THEIR
RESPONSIBILITIES AS THE CARETAKERS OF THIS PLACE AS
WELL AS FOR ALL PEOPLES WHO RESIDE IN THEIR TRADITIONAL
TERRITORY AS GUESTS WE RECOGNIZE THAT WE BENEFIT FROM
LIVING AND WORKING ON THEIR TRADITIONAL HOMELAND.
WE WISH TO PAY OUR RESPECTS BY ACKNOWLEDGING THE ANCESTORS,
ELDERS AND RELATIVES OF THE RAW MATERIAL OWNING COMMUNITY
AND BY AFFIRMING THEIR SOVEREIGN RIGHTS AS FIRST
PEOPLES. COLLEAGUES, WILL YOU JOIN ME
IN RECITING THE PLEDGE OF ALLEGIANCE?
I PLEDGE ALLEGIANCE TO THE FLAG OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA
TO THE REPUBLIC FOR WHICH IT STANDS ONE NATION UNDER GOD
INDIVISIBLE WITH LIBERTY AND JUSTICE FOR ALL.
>> AND ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD I WOULD LIKE TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE
STAFF AT US OF GOV TV AND IN PARTICULAR TODAY KALEENA
MENDOZA. >> THEY RECORD EACH OF OUR
MEETINGS AND MAKE THE TRANSCRIPTS AVAILABLE TO THE
PUBLIC ONLINE. >> MADAM CLERK, DO YOU HAVE ANY
COMMUNICATIONS? >> THANK YOU MR. PRESIDENT.
THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS WELCOMES YOU ALL TO
ATTEND THIS MEETING HERE IN THE BOARD'S LEGISLATIVE CHAMBER
WITHIN CITY HALL ON THE SECOND FLOOR ROOM 250.
IF YOU CAN'T MAKE IT TO THE CHAMBER YOU MAY WATCH THE
PROCEEDING ON SFP OF TVS CHANNEL 26 OR VIEW THE
LIVESTREAM AT W W W DOT S.F. GEO V VTV.ORG.
YOU MAY SUBMIT YOUR PUBLIC COMMENT IN WRITING.
YOU CAN SEND AN EMAIL TO BOISE AT S.F. GOV ORG OR USE THE
POSTAL SERVICE JUST ADDRESS YOUR ENVELOPE TO THE SAN
FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS THE NUMBER ONE DR. CARLTON B
GOODLATTE PLACE CITY HALL ROOM 244 SAN FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA
94102. TO MAKE A REASONABLE
ACCOMMODATION REQUEST UNDER THE AMERICANS WITH DISABILITIES ACT
OR TO REQUEST LANGUAGE ASSISTANCE YOU CAN CONTACT THE
CLERK'S OFFICE IN ROOM 244. CONTACT US AT LEAST TWO
BUSINESS DAYS IN ADVANCE BY CALLING (415) 554-5184.
>> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
>> LET'S GO TO THE APPROVAL OF OUR MEETING MINUTES.
THE APPROVAL OF THE APRIL 22ND, 2025 AND THE APRIL 29TH 2025
REGULAR BOARD MEETING MINUTES AND THE APRIL 30TH 2025 SPECIAL
MEETING MINUTES AT THE BUDGET AND APPROPRIATIONS COMMITTEE
MEETING WHICH CONSTITUTED A QUORUM OF THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS. >> DO WE HAVE ANY CHANGES TO
THE MINUTES? I DON'T SEE ANYBODY.
CAN I HAVE A MOTION TO APPROVE THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED MOVED
BY MELGAR SECONDED BY CHERYL. MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL ON THE MINUTES SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN.
>> I MENDELSON I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR
SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON EYES
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR ENGARDIO
AND ENGARDIO I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I
AND SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I THERE ARE 11 EYES WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE MINUTES WILL BE APPROVED AFTER PUBLIC COMMENT
AS PRESENTED. MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO OUR
CONSENT AGENDA ITEMS ONE THROUGH EIGHT ITEMS ONE THROUGH
EIGHT ARE ON CONSENT. >> THESE ITEMS ARE CONSIDERED
TO BE ROUTINE. IF A MEMBER OBJECTS AN ITEM MAY
BE REMOVED AND CONSIDERED SEPARATELY.
>> DOES ANYONE WANT TO SEVER ANY ITEMS FROM THE CONSENT
AGENDA I DON'T SEE. OH YES.
YES. YES.
SUPERVISOR CHERYL SLIKE TO BE ADDED AS A CO-SPONSOR ON NUMBER
THREE NOTED RIGHTS. I DON'T SEE ANYONE ELSE MADAM
CLERK CAN YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEMS ONE THROUGH EIGHT
SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI MANDEL MAN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR
I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON EYES SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN I
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR ENGARDIO AND ENGARDIO I SUPERVISOR
FIELDER FIELDER I AND SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD
I THERE ARE 11 EYES WITHOUT OBJECTION THESE ORDINANCE ARE
PASSED THESE ORDINANCES ARE PASSED ON FIRST READING
AND FINALLY PASSED MADAM CLERK CAN YOU PLEASE CALL THE REGULAR
AGENDA NEW BUSINESS ITEM IS NINE AND TEN TOGETHER ITEMS
NINE AND 10 OR 2 ORDINANCES THAT PERTAIN TO CERTIFICATES OF
PARTICIPATION. ITEM NINE AUTHORIZES THE
EXECUTION AND DELIVERY OF CERTIFICATES OF PARTICIPATION
IN ONE OR MORE SERIES FROM TIME TO TIME TO REAP PREPAY RENTAL
PAYMENTS DUE TO U.S. BANK TRUST COMPANY NATIONAL ASSOCIATION AS
SUCCESSOR PROJECT TRUSTEE DUE UNDER A PROJECT LEASE DATED
JULY 1ST, 2017 BY AND BETWEEN THE PROJECT TRUSTEE AND THE
CITY TO APPROVE MULTIPLE FORMS AGREEMENTS, LEASES, LEASEBACK
NOTICES AND PURCHASE CONTRACT A PURCHASE CONTRACT TO APPROVE
THE FORM OF A PURCHASE CONTRACT BETWEEN THE CITY AND ONE OR
MORE INITIAL PURCHASERS OF THE CERTIFICATES AND FOR ITEM TEN
THIS ORDINANCE APPROPRIATES 379 MILLION CONSISTING OF 350
MILLION OF REFUNDING CERTIFICATES OF PARTICIPATION
SERIES 2025 ARE PROCEEDS AND 29 MILLION OF SERIES 2017 B PRIOR
DEBT SERVICE RESERVE TO THE REFUNDING CERTIFICATES OF
PARTICIPATION SERIES 2025 ARE AND TO PLACE FUNDS ON
CONTROLLERS RESERVE PENDING THE SALE OF THE CERTIFICATES OF
PARTICIPATION IN FISCAL YEARS 2024 THROUGH 2025.
LET'S TAKE THESE ITEMS SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE ORDINANCES ARE PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM
CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 11 ITEM 11 THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO
AMEND THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO INCREASE THE FOLLOWING
ASSESSMENT APPEALS BOARD FEES ADMINISTRATIVE PROCESSING FEES,
HEARING FEES AND FEES FOR WRITTEN FINDINGS.
>> AND LET'S TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM
CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 12 ITEM 12 THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO
AMEND THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO INCREASE THE FEES TO SELL AT
CITY OPERATED FARMER'S MARKETS AND AT THE ALMATY FLEA MARKET.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THIS
ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL
ITEM 13 ITEM 13 THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO APPROPRIATE
APPROXIMATELY 7.9 MILLION OF AMBULANCE SERVICE REVENUE
IN THE FIRE DEPARTMENT TO APPROPRIATE 1.5 MILLION
IN PERMANENT SALARIES IN THE DEPARTMENT OF EMERGENCY
MANAGEMENT APPROXIMATELY 866,000 IN THE FIRE DEPARTMENT
,500,000 IN THE PUBLIC UTILITIES COMMISSION
AND APPROXIMATE AMOUNT OF 3.7 MILLION TO THE PERMANENT
SALARIES AND APPROXIMATELY 5 MILLION TO OVERTIME IN THE FIRE
DEPARTMENT AND 1.5 MILLION TO OVERTIME IN THE DEPARTMENT OF
EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT 500,000 TO OVERTIME IN THE PUBLIC
UTILITIES COMMISSION IN ORDER TO SUPPORT THE DEPARTMENT'S
PROJECTED INCREASES IN OVERTIME IN FISCAL YEAR 2024 THROUGH
2025. THIS ORDINANCE REQUIRES A TWO
THIRDS VOTE OF ALL MEMBERS OF THE BOARD FOR APPROVAL OF THE
FIRE DEPARTMENT'S APPROPRIATION OF APPROXIMATELY 7.9 MILLION.
>> AND I THINK WE CAN TAKE THIS SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE ORDINANCES PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK
PLEASE CALL ITEM 14 ITEM 14 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO
RETROACTIVELY AUTHORIZE THE ADULT PROBATION DEPARTMENT TO
ACCEPT AND EXPEND A $1.5 MILLION GRANT FROM THE
CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH CARE SERVICES FOR A STATEWIDE
PROGRAM ENTITLED CAL AIM I PATH ROUND THREE FUNDING FOR THE
TERM OF JANUARY 31ST, 2025 THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2026.
>> LET'S TAKE THIS SAME HOUSE SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED MADAM CLERK
PLEASE CALL ITEM 15 ITEM 15 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO APPROVE
THE SECOND MODIFICATION TO AN AIRPORT CONTRACT CAPITAL
PROGRAM SUPPORT SERVICES FOR THE CAPITAL IMPROVEMENT PLAN
FOR THE SAN FRANCISCO INTERNATIONAL AIRPORT WITH T Y
LIN INTERNATIONAL TO INCREASE THE CONTRACT AMOUNT BY 32
MILLION FOR A NEW CONTRACT AMOUNT OF 40 MILLION AND TO
EXTEND THE CONTRACT FOR AN ADDITIONAL FOUR YEARS OF
SERVICE THROUGH SEPTEMBER 29TH 2029 AND WILL TAKE THIS SAME
HOUSE SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS
ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL
ITEM 16 THROUGH 18 TOGETHER ITEMS 16 THROUGH 18 HERE WE
HAVE THREE RESOLUTIONS THAT APPROVE AGREEMENTS FOR THE
DEPARTMENT OF HOMELESSNESS AND SUPPORT OF HOUSING.
ITEM 16 APPROVES THE SECOND AMENDMENT TO THE GRANT
AGREEMENT WITH EPISCOPAL COMMUNITY SERVICES FOR SUPPORT
SERVICES PROPERTY MANAGEMENT AND MASTER LIST STEWARDSHIP AT
THE ALDER, THE CROSBY THE ELM, THE HILLSDALE AND THE MINTON
HOTELS FOR PERMANENT SUPPORTIVE HOUSING FOR FORMERLY HOMELESS
ADULTS TO EXTEND THE GRANT TERM BY 424 MONTHS NOW THROUGH JUNE
30TH 2027 TO INCREASE THE AGREEMENT AMOUNT BY
APPROXIMATELY 25 MILLION FOR A NEW TOTAL AMOUNT OF
APPROXIMATELY 72.2 MILLION. ITEM 17 APPROVES THE THIRD
AMENDMENT TO THE GRANT AGREEMENT WITH FIVE KEYS
SCHOOLS AND PROGRAMS TO PROVIDE EMERGENCY SHELTER OPERATIONS
AND SERVICES AT NEXT DOOR SHELTER TO INCREASE THE GRANT
AMOUNT BY APPROXIMATELY 26.7 MILLION FOR A NEW TOTAL OF
APPROXIMATELY 59.2 MILLION AND TO EXTEND THE GRANT
AGREEMENT TERM BY 36 MONTHS NOW THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2028 AND FOR
ITEM 18 ITEM 18 TO APPROVE AND AUTHORIZE THE DIRECTOR OF
PROPERTY AND THE EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF THE DEPARTMENT OF
HOMELESSNESS AND SUPPORT OF HOUSING TO APPROVE THE
ASSIGNMENT OF THE CERTAIN LEASE AND PROPERTY MANAGEMENT
AGREEMENT DATED FEBRUARY 17TH 2023 BY AND BETWEEN THE CITY
AND THE TIDE CENTER AS FISCAL SPONSOR TO DELIVER INNOVATION
IN SUPPORT OF HOUSING FOR THE REAL PROPERTY LOCATED AT 1321
MISSION STREET FROM TIDES TO DISH S.F. A NONPROFIT PUBLIC
BENEFIT CORPORATION TO BECOME EFFECTIVE JULY 1ST, 2025
AND WILL TAKE THESE ITEMS SAME HOUSE SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION THESE RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 19 ITEM 19 THIS IS A RESOLUTION
THAT APPROVES THE EXECUTION OF A FIRST AMENDMENT TO THE SENIOR
OPERATING SUBSIDY GRANT AGREEMENT WITH CHINATOWN
SORROWS LLC TO INCREASE THE GRANT AMOUNT BY 572,000 FOR A
NEW GRANT TOTAL AMOUNT OF 6.7 MILLION TO FULLY FUND THE 15
YEAR AND SIX MONTH TERM THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2039 WITH RENT
SUBSIDY FOR 35 EXTREMELY LOW INCOME SENIORS AT 1005 POWELL
STREET A 64 UNIT 100% AFFORDABLE MULTIFAMILY RENTAL
HOUSING DEVELOPMENT. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THIS RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL OUT AND 20 ITEM 20 IS A RESOLUTION
TO APPROVE FOR THE PURPOSES OF THE INTERNAL REVENUE CODE OF
1986 THE ISSUANCE AND SALE OF REVENUE OBLIGATIONS BY THE
CALIFORNIA ENTERPRISE DEVELOPMENT AUTHORITY IN AN
AGGREGATE PRINCIPAL AMOUNT OF 15 MILLION TO FINANCE OR
REFINANCE THE COST OF ACQUISITION CONSTRUCTION
INSTALLATION, REHABILITATION, EQUIPPING AND FURNISHING OF
VARIOUS CAPITAL FACILITIES TO BE OWNED AND OPERATED BY THE
CALIFORNIA INSTITUTE OF INTEGRAL STUDIES.
CALIFORNIA NONPROFIT PUBLIC BENEFIT CORPORATION AND SAME
HOUSE SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION, THIS RESOLUTION IS
ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL
ITEM 21 ITEM 21 THIS IS A MOTION TO ENACT A 4.50% COST OF
LIVING ADJUSTMENT FOR THE BASE FISCAL YEAR OF 2024 THROUGH 25
CONTRACT AMOUNT OF APPROXIMATELY 3.2 MILLION FOR
BUDGET AND LEGISLATIVE ANALYST SERVICES TO BE EFFECTUATED AS
OF JULY 1ST 2025 RESULTING IN A NEW FISCAL YEAR 20 2526
CONTRACT AMOUNT OF 3.4 MILLION AN ANNUAL INCREASE OF 146,000
AND A NEW TOTAL CONTRACT AMOUNT OF 36 MILLION FOR THE CONTRACT
TERM ENDING DECEMBER 31ST, 2031 AND SAME HOUSE SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THIS MOTION IS APPROVED.
>> MADAM CLERK, COULD YOU PLEASE CALL ITEMS 22 AND 23
TOGETHER? ITEM 22 AND 23 PERTAIN TO THE
ESTABLISHMENT OF THE SAN FRANCISCO DOWNTOWN
REVITALIZATION AND ECONOMIC RECOVERY FINANCING DISTRICT.
ITEM 22 IS THE RESOLUTION OF INTENTION TO ESTABLISH THE
REVITALIZATION AND ECONOMIC RECOVERY FINANCING DISTRICT TO
FINANCE COMMERCIAL TO RESIDENTIAL CONVERSION PROJECTS
AND OTHER AUTHORIZED COSTS TO DETERMINE THE BOUNDARIES OF THE
DISTRICT TO STATE THE NEED FOR THE DISTRICT GOALS THE DISTRICT
AND ITS GOALS THE DISTRICT PROPOSES TO ACHIEVE TO DESCRIBE
THE USE OF PROPERTY TAX REVENUE THAT WILL BE USED TO FINANCE
THE DISTRICT'S ACTIVITIES TO AUTHORIZE THE ESTABLISHMENT OF
THE TIME AND DATE FOR A PUBLIC HEARING ON THE PLAN AND TO MAKE
THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS. ITEM 23 THIS IS THE ORDINANCE
TO AMEND THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO ESTABLISH AND DEFINE
THE MEMBERSHIP AND DUTIES OF THE BOARD OF DIRECTORS OF THE
SAN FRANCISCO DOWNTOWN REVITALIZATION AND ECONOMIC
RECOVERY FINANCING DISTRICT SUPERVISOR DORSEY THANK YOU
PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN. BEFORE OFFERING THE AMENDMENTS
THAT MY STAFF CIRCULATED YESTERDAY TO ITEM 23 I WANTED
TO BRIEFLY EXPRESS MY STRONG SUPPORT FOR THE CREATION OF THE
DOWNTOWN REVITALIZATION AND ECONOMIC RECOVERY FINANCING
DISTRICT. THAT THESE ITEMS WILL ESTABLISH
THIS DISTRICT WILL PROVIDE THE CITY WITH ANOTHER TOOL TO
INCENTIVIZE ADAPTIVE REUSE PROJECT X SO THAT WE CAN BOTH
FACILITATE THE PRODUCTION OF MUCH NEEDED HOUSING AND HELP
BRING NEW LIFE TO UNDER ACTIVATED PARTS OF THE CITY.
I'M VERY OPTIMISTIC THAT THIS WILL HELP FULFILL THE VISION OF
A MORE THRIVING RESIDENTIAL DOWNTOWN.
I'M GRATEFUL TO OUR OWN FORMER ASSEMBLY MEMBER PHIL TING FOR
HIS LEADERSHIP ON THE STATE LEGISLATION AB 2488 THAT ALLOWS
US TO DO THIS. I'M ALSO GRATEFUL TO
MAYOR LURIE THE PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN ALL OF MY FELLOW
CO-SPONSORS AND ALL THE CITY STAFF FOR THEIR WORK ON THIS.
THANK YOU ALSO TO CHAIR CHAN FOR YOUR THOUGHTFUL REMARKS.
TWO WEEKS AGO IN THE BUDGET COMMITTEE ON THIS THE COMMITTEE
HAD A ROBUST DISCUSSION ABOUT REIMBURSEMENTS.
STATE LAW EXPLICITLY STATES THAT THE DISTRICT SHALL BE
REIMBURSED OR THE CITY DEPARTMENTS SHALL BE REIMBURSED
FOR THE SUPPORT THAT WE PROVIDE THIS BUT FOR PURPOSES OF
CONSISTENCY AND CLARITY I WOULD LIKE TO INCLUDE SIMILAR
LANGUAGE HERE. THIS IS AS I UNDERSTAND IT A
NON SUBSTANTIVE AMENDMENT SO I'D LIKE TO MAKE A MOTION TO
ADD THE FOLLOWING LANGUAGE TO ITEM 23 THE ORDINANCE ON PAGE
EIGHT LINE SIX I'M SORRY PAGE SIX, LINE EIGHT SUBSECTION M AS
PERMITTED BY THE DOWNTOWN REVITALIZATION LAW ALL COSTS
INCURRED BY ANY OTHER CITY DEPARTMENT IN CONNECTION WITH
THE CREATION MANAGEMENT OR OTHER ADMINISTRATIVE SUPPORT
FOR THE DOWNTOWN REVITALIZATION DISTRICT SHALL BE PAID BY THE
DOWNTOWN REVITALIZATION DISTRICT.
SO I'D LIKE TO MAKE THAT A MOTION TO AMEND AND AFTER THAT
MOTION I HOPE THIS WILL PASS ON FIRST READING THANK YOU
SUPERVISOR DORSEY FOR YOUR COMMENTS AND FOR YOUR MOTION.
>> IS THERE A SECOND SECONDED BY CHAN THIS MOTION AND A
SECOND COLLEAGUES CAN WE TAKE THAT PROPOSED AMENDMENT TO ITEM
23? WITHOUT OBJECTION I THINK WE
CAN. AND THEN MADAM CLERK, WE I
THINK WE CAN TAKE THESE ITEMS SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION. THE RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED AND MR.
PRESIDENT WITHOUT HIM 23 AS AMENDED AND THE AMENDED
ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING YEAH.
ALL RIGHT, MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 24.
>> ITEM 24. THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO WAIVE
THE CONTRACTING REQUIREMENTS OF THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE FOR
TENANT IMPROVEMENTS PERFORMED BY KARST AT LARGE LLC A
PROSPECTIVE OF PORT TENANT OR ITS AGENTS FOR THE LEASE WITH
THE PORT OF SAN FRANCISCO FOR PROPERTY AT PIER 29 APPROVED BY
THE PORT COMMISSION. AND WE CAN TAKE THIS SAME HOUSE
SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST
READING AND MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO OUR COMMITTEE REPORTS.
>> ITEMS 25 THROUGH 27 WERE CONSIDERED BY THE LAND USE
AND TRANSPORTATION COMMITTEE AT A REGULAR MEETING ON MONDAY
JUNE SECOND, 2025 AND WERE FORWARDED AS COMMITTEE REPORTS
. CAN YOU CALL 25 AND 26
TOGETHER? >> ITEMS 25 AND 26 ARE
IN RECOGNITION OF DR. AMOS C BROWN'S LIFETIME OF LEADERSHIP
IN CIVIL RIGHTS AND COMMUNITY BUILDING IN SAN FRANCISCO
AND AROUND THE WORLD UPON HIS RETIREMENT AS SENIOR PASTOR OF
THE THIRD BAPTIST CHURCH. ITEM 25 IS THE RESOLUTION TO
DECLARE THE INTENTION OF THE BOARD TO RENAME THE 809 HUNDRED
BLOCKS OF PIERCE STREET FROM FULTON STREET TO GOLDEN GATE
AVENUE TO DR. AMOS C BROWN WAY. ITEM 26 IS THE RESOLUTION TO
ADD THE COMMEMORATIVE STREET NAME DR. AMOS C BROWN WAY TO
THE 809 HUNDRED BLOCKS OF PIERCE STREET FROM FULTON
STREET TO GOLDEN GATE AVENUE. >> ALL RIGHT.
WE CAN TAKE THESE ITEMS SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT
OBJECTION, MR. PRESIDENT. >> YEP.
>> WE HAVE A SUPERVISOR WHO LEFT THE HOUSE.
OH, WE NEED TO DO A ROLL CALL. >> THANK YOU ON ITEMS 25 AND 26
SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN I RANDLEMAN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I
SUPERVISOR SARTOR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN I
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHIN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR ENGARDIO AND ENGARDIO I SUPERVISOR
FIELDER FIELDER I AND SUPERVISOR ONE MAHMOOD I
THERE ARE 11 EYES ALL RIGHT WITHOUT OBJECTION THESE
RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 27 ITEM
27 THIS ITEM WAS RECOMMENDED AS AMENDED WITH THE SAME TITLE.
IT'S A RESOLUTION TO AUTHORIZE THE PLANNING DEPARTMENT TO
APPLY ON BEHALF OF THE CITY AND COUNTY TO CONFIRM EXISTING
AND CREATE NEW AND REVISED DESIGNATIONS OF PRIORITY
CONSERVATION AREAS BY THE ASSOCIATION OF BAY AREA
GOVERNMENTS AND THE METROPOLITAN TRANSPORTATION
COMMISSION. AND WE CAN TAKE THIS SAME HOUSE
SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 28.
>> ITEM 28 WAS CONSIDERED BY THE RULES COMMITTEE AT A
REGULAR MEETING ON MONDAY, JUNE 2ND, 2025 AND WAS FORWARDED AS
AMENDED AS A COMMITTEE REPORT STRIKING THE WORD REJECTING
AND THE NEW TITLE NOW READS ITEM 28 IS A MOTION TO APPROVE
THE MAYOR'S NOMINATION FOR APPOINTMENT OF KEN MCNEELY TO
THE PORT COMMISSION TERM ENDING MAY 1ST, 2029.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTION
IS APPROVED. >> MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO A
ROLL CALL FIRST MEMBER UP TO INTRODUCE NEW BUSINESS IS
SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN. >> ALL RIGHT COLLEAGUES, I WILL
SUBMIT MY LEGISLATION AND I AM ALSO REQUESTING THAT WE ADJOURN
TODAY'S MEETING IN MEMORY OF STEVE KELLERMAN WHO DIED ON
APRIL 27TH AT THE AGE OF 83. STEVE WAS BORN IN 1941 AND GREW
UP IN PHILADELPHIA. HIS FAMILY WAS TIGHT KNIT.
HIS MOTHER WAS BORN INTO AN IMMIGRANT FAMILY LIVING ON THE
LOWER EAST SIDE OF MANHATTAN. AFTER LIVING FOR A TIME IN NEW
YORK, THE SIBLINGS SETTLED AROUND PHILADELPHIA
AND REMAINED CLOSE FOR THE REST OF THEIR LIVES.
STEVE'S MOTHER PASSED ON TO HIM A SENSE OF COMMUNITY AND CARE
FOR OTHERS THAT STAYED WITH HIM THROUGHOUT HIS LIFE.
AFTER GRADUATING FROM TEMPLE UNIVERSITY IN 1964, STEVE MOVED
TO SAN FRANCISCO TO JOIN THE AIR FORCE RESERVES AND EARNED
HIS MASTER'S DEGREE IN INDUSTRIAL PSYCHOLOGY AT SAN
FRANCISCO STATE UNIVERSITY. AFTER RECEIVING HIS MASTER'S,
STEVE JOINED THE FEDERATED DEPARTMENT STORES INC THE
PARENT COMPANY OF MACY'S IN THEIR H.R.
DEPARTMENT. WHILE WORKING AT FEDERATED HE
MET HIS FUTURE WIFE SUSAN WALKING DOWN UNION STREET ONE
DAY IN 1970. STEVE ASKED STUART SUSAN WHO
WAS CARRYING A VACUUM SHE HAD BORROWED FROM A FRIEND IF HE
COULD BORROW IT WHEN SHE WAS DONE.
SUSAN, WHO DIED IN AUGUST OF LAST YEAR AND STEVE MARRIED A
YEAR LATER AND REMAINED TOGETHER FOR THE REST OF THEIR
LIVES. >> STEVE WAS AHEAD OF HIS TIME
IN THE LATE 1970S DURING THE OIL EMBARGO.
A PICTURE OF STEVE RIDING HIS BIKE ON HIS MORNING COMMUTE
DOWNTOWN MADE THE FRONT PAGE OF THE SAN FRANCISCO CHRONICLE.
AROUND THE SAME TIME HE FOUNDED HIS OWN CONSULTING FIRM
KELLERMANN AND ASSOCIATES. KELLERMANN ASSOCIATES
SPECIALIZED IN PUTTING TOGETHER AFFIRMATIVE ACTION HIRING PLANS
FOR LARGE CORPORATIONS IN ALL ASPECTS OF HIS LIFE.
STEVE TRIED TO BETTER HIS COMMUNITY IN THE 1970S.
HE ORGANIZED HIS NEIGHBORS TO GET THE FIRST SPEED BUMPS ADDED
ON CUMBERLAND STREET NEAR DELORES PARK.
AFTER MOVING TO NO VALLEY, HE HELPED UNDERGROUND THE
ELECTRICAL WIRES IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD ALTHOUGH HE FAILED
TO ACCOMPLISH THAT GOAL FOR HIS OWN STREET.
>> THROUGHOUT HIS PROFESSIONAL CAREER HE WAS INVOLVED IN THE
BIG BROTHERS PROGRAM AS HIS OWN AS HIS OWN SON ZACH STARTED
SCHOOL. STEVE JOINED THE BOARD OF
TRUSTEES AT THE BRANDEIS LITTLE OLD SCHOOL ON BROTHERHOOD WAY.
TODAY THE BRANDEIS SCHOOL IN HIS EARLY 60S, STEVE
TRANSFORMED HIS FAVORITE WAY TO COMMUTE AND EXERCISE HIS BIKE
INTO A WAY TO DO GOOD. HE SERVED AS A COACH FOR TEAM
AND TRAINING, WRITING THOUSANDS OF MILES AND RAISING HUNDREDS
OF THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS FOR LYMPHOMA RESEARCH.
HE CONTINUED TO CYCLE INTO HIS 70S.
>> AT 75 HE RODE AROUND LAKE TAHOE.
>> STEVE STEVE'S LIFE FROM HIS CAREER TO HIS FREE TIME
REVOLVED AROUND HIS LOVE FOR PEOPLE.
HE WAS A SOCIAL GUY WITH A BIG PERSONALITY AND HE LOVED TO
DANCE. OVER THE LAST DECADE STEVE
STRUGGLED WITH DEMENTIA. HE MOVED INTO THE MEMORY CARE
FACILITY IN THE FRANK RESIDENCE AT THE JEWISH HOME FOR THE LAST
FOUR YEARS OF HIS LIFE. NEVERTHELESS, HE REMAINED THE
LIFE OF THE PARTY FOR HIS GRANDDAUGHTER'S BAT MITZVAH.
HE CAME IN A WHEELCHAIR BUT REFUSING TO BE SIDELINED HE HIT
THE DANCE FLOOR ONCE AGAIN. STEVE SURVIVED BY HIS SON ZACH,
HIS DAUGHTER IN LAW ANDREA AND HIS TWO GRANDCHILDREN
SHOSHANA AND JACOB. >> ASKED TO DESCRIBE HIS DAD'S
,ZACH SAID HE WAS A FORCE HE NEVER FADED INTO THE CROWD.
HE WAS ALWAYS IN THE FRONT. HE WAS ALWAYS THERE.
STEVE KELLERMAN, YOU WILL BE MISSED.
REST IN PEACE AND MAY YOUR MEMORY BE A BLESSING AND THE
REST I SUBMIT. THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
WE HAVE TWO MINUTES LEFT. SUPERVISOR MELGAR.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. COLLEAGUES TODAY I'M
INTRODUCING ALONG WITH SUPERVISOR CHERYL AND STARTER
LEGISLATION TO MAKE IT EASIER TO FILL VACANT SPACES AND TO
PROVIDE MORE FLEXIBILITY FOR NEW BUSINESSES TRYING TO EXPAND
. THIS LEGISLATION WOULD DO TWO
THINGS ONE ELIMINATE CAPS ON STOREFRONT SIZES IN CERTAIN
NEIGHBORHOOD COMMERCIAL DISTRICT AND INSTEAD REQUIRE A
CONDITIONAL USE AUTHORIZATION. THIS WOULD ALLOW NEIGHBORHOOD
FEEDBACK ON A CASE BY CASE BASIS.
IN THE PAST WE HAD TO PASS A LEGISLATION SPECIFIC TO A
BUSINESS OR SITE WHICH IS NOT REALLY GREAT POLICY.
>> AND THE SECOND THING WE WOULD DO IS REMOVE THE
CONDITIONAL USE REQUIREMENT FOR SPACES THAT SUBDIVIDE IF THEY
ARE GETTING CLOSER TO CONFORMITY WITH A CODE.
THIS ALEMAO THIS WILL ALLOW SMALLER BUSINESSES TO FILL
LARGER SPACES AND THAT IS SOMETHING WE ALL WANT.
>> WE ARE FACING DIFFERENT ECONOMIC CHALLENGES TODAY WITH
EVOLVING BUSINESS MODELS AND VACANCIES THAT ARE
DIFFICULT TO FILL IN OUR CURRENT MARKET ESPECIALLY
LARGER SPACES LIKE THE MANY WALGREENS THAT HAVE BECOME
EMPTY. THIS IS ONE PART OF A
LEGISLATIVE PACKAGE I HOPE WILL ALLEVIATE SOME OF THE
CHALLENGES IN A THOUGHTFUL WAY. I WANT TO EXTEND MY THANKS TO
HEATHER GOODMAN AND JULIA WALKER NELSON AT THE CITY
ATTORNEY'S OFFICE AND ESPECIALLY TO AUDREY MALONE
AT THE PLANNING DEPARTMENT FOR THEIR SUPPORT ON THIS DRAFTING
THIS LEGISLATION. >> I ALSO WANT TO ANNOUNCE THAT
YOU MAY REMEMBER COLLEAGUES THAT LAST YEAR WE HELD A
HEARING THAT PROMPTED AN AUDIT OF THE SAN FRANCISCO ZOOLOGICAL
SOCIETY. AT THAT AUDIT HAS NOT GONE WELL
AND I HAVE REQUESTED TO BUDGET CHAIR CHAN TO CONSIDER A MOTION
AT THE BUDGET COMMITTEE TO HOLD THE FUNDING FOR THE ZOO
IN RESERVE TO INCENTIVIZE COOPERATION IN COMPLIANCE WITH
THE AUDIT. I AM GRATEFUL THAT SHE WOULD
ENTERTAIN THE REQUEST AND WE WILL HOPEFULLY BE ABLE TO
SUPPORT THIS ORGANIZATION AS THEY BECOME SUCCESSFUL,
TRANSPARENT AND ACCOUNTABLE. AND THE REST I SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. LET'S GO TO OUR 230 SPECIAL
ORDER. THE SPECIAL ORDER AT 230 IS THE
RECOGNITION OF COMMENDATIONS FOR MERITORIOUS SERVICE TO THE
CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> ALL RIGHT, COLLEAGUES NOW NORMALLY I HAVE MYSELF GO LARGE
FIRST. BUT TODAY IN LIGHT OF THE FACT
THAT MY HONOREE IS OUR POLICE CHIEF, I THINK WE'RE GOING TO
I'M GOING TO TAKE A PRIVILEGE AND PUT MYSELF FIRST WITH
APOLOGIES. >> IF THERE ARE NO OBJECTIONS.
CHIEF SCOTT, PLEASE COME FORWARD.
>> I SAID SOME OF THESE NICE THINGS ABOUT AN HOUR AND A HALF
AGO IN THE MAYOR'S CEREMONIAL ROOM.
I WILL BE HONEST THIS IS A BITTERSWEET COMMENDATION FOR
ME. >> I'M NOT HAPPY.
THIS IS I WILL NOTE CERTAINLY NOT THE FIRST TIME THIS BOARD
HAS HONORED CHIEF SCOTT. ANY NUMBER OF US HAVE
RECOGNIZED HIM OVER THE YEARS FOR HIS EXTRAORDINARY SERVICE
TO THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO AND THAT HAS BEEN
WELL-DESERVED. BUT THIS IS SADLY OUR FINAL
OPPORTUNITY TO RECOGNIZE AND THANK HIM WHILE HE'S STILL
CHIEF OF OUR SAN FRANCISCO POLICE DEPARTMENT.
AFTER EIGHT YEARS LEADING THAT DEPARTMENT CHIEF SCOTT'S FINAL
DAY WILL BE JUNE 22ND. >> NINE YEARS AGO IN THE WAKE
OF MULTIPLE OFFICER INVOLVED FACE THAT FATALITIES A RACIST
TEXT MESSAGE SCANDAL INCREASINGLY FRAUGHT TO PUT IT
MILDLY RELATIONS BETWEEN CITY ELECTED OFFICIALS AND THE POPE
. AND AMID INCREASING COMMUNITY
FRUSTRATION WITH THE PACE OF REFORM, THE POLICE COMMISSION
BEGAN ITS SEARCH FOR SAN FRANCISCO'S NEXT POLICE CHIEF.
>> DURING THAT SEARCH, THE UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF
JUSTICE'S OFFICE OF COMMUNITY ORIENTED POLICING SERVICES
RELEASED THE RESULTS OF A SIX MONTH LONG INVESTIGATION INTO
THE S.F. PD. AN INVESTIGATION INITIATED AT
MAYOR LEE'S REQUEST. >> THE REPORT FOUND THE
DEPARTMENT DEFICIENT IN EVERY OPERATIONAL AREA ASSESSED
AND INCLUDED 272 RECOMMENDED CHANGES.
THE DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE CALLED FOR THE REPORT TO BE A
GUIDING LIGHT IN SAN FRANCISCO'S HIRING PROCESS,
SUGGESTING THAT THE RECOMMENDATIONS WOULD REQUIRE
DEDICATED AND FOCUSED LEADERSHIP.
JANUARY OF 2017 MERELY SWORE IN BILL SCOTT AS THE CHIEF OF
THE SAN FRANCISCO POLICE DEPARTMENT.
HE WAS AT THE TIME A 27 YEAR VETERAN OF THE LOS ANGELES
POLICE DEPARTMENT WHO'D RISEN FROM A PATROL OFFICER TO DEPUTY
CHIEF OF THE LAPD'S SOUTH BUREAU.
HAVING GROWN UP IN BIRMINGHAM, ALABAMA IN THE YEARS FOLLOWING
THE CIVIL RIGHTS MOVEMENT, SCOTT WAS KNOWN IN SOUTH L.A.
FOR HIS ABILITY TO EMPATHIZE WITH RESIDENTS AND HIS
COMMITMENT TO IMPROVING THEIR RELATIONSHIPS WITH THE POLICE.
>> IN SAN FRANCISCO HIS COMMITMENT TO REFORM WAS
IMMEDIATELY TESTED WHEN THE DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE UNDER THE
FIRST TRUMP ADMINISTRATION DECIDED IT WAS NO LONGER
WILLING TO OVERSEE THE IMPLEMENTATION OF ITS OWN
RECOMMENDATIONS. HE SOUGHT INDEPENDENT OVERSIGHT
FROM THE CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE.
IN JANUARY OF THIS YEAR. CALIFORNIA DOJ FOUND THE SFPD
COMPLIANT WITH 97% OF THE 272 RECOMMENDATIONS.
CHIEF SCOTT HAD ACCOMPLISHED THE MONUMENTAL MISSION FOR
WHICH HE WAS HIRED. >> THAT RECORD OF REFORM ALONE
WOULD HAVE BEEN A PROUD LEGACY FOR ANY POLICE CHIEF.
HOWEVER, THE COVID 19 PANDEMIC. GEORGE FLOYD'S SUMMER A
NATIONWIDE CRIME SURGE POST-PANDEMIC AND THE
PROLIFERATION OF ENCAMPMENTS AND DRUG SCENES IN PUBLIC
SPACES IN NEIGHBORHOODS ACROSS SAN FRANCISCO EACH PRESENTED
WHAT AT OTHER TIMES WOULD HAVE BEEN A GENERATIONAL CHALLENGE
FOR A METROPOLITAN POLICE DEPARTMENT.
CHIEF SCOTT NEVER LOST HIS COOL AND ROSE TO MEET EVERY
CHALLENGE PRESENTED. AND IN A CITY THAT IS
NOTORIOUSLY TOUGH ON COPS, CHIEF SCOTT MAINTAINED THE
TRUST OF COMMUNITY AND THEIR ELECTED OFFICIALS.
AS THE LONGEST SERVING POLICE CHIEF SINCE 1970, HE'S WORKED
WITH FOUR MAYORS FOR DISTRICT ATTORNEYS, SCORES OF POLICE
COMMISSION COMMISSIONERS AND MEMBERS OF THIS BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS. SAN FRANCISCANS ARE A FRACTIOUS
BUNCH AND THEIR ELECTED AND APPOINTED OFFICIALS REFLECT
A DIVERSITY OF PASSIONATELY HELD PERSPECTIVES.
AND YET I'VE BEEN STRUCK THAT SO MANY PEOPLE WHO DISAGREE ON
SO MANY SOCIAL AND CRIMINAL JUSTICE POLICY QUESTIONS AGREE
ON THE EXCELLENCE, HONESTY, INTEGRITY AND FUNDAMENTAL
DECENCY OF BILL SCOTT. >> TODAY WE ARE LIVING IN A
SAFER CITY BECAUSE OF CHIEF SCOTT.
>> FROM 2017 TO 2024 CRIME ACROSS ALL CATEGORIES DROPPED
42%. THIS YEAR CRIME CONTINUES TO
FALL AT DOUBLE DIGIT RATES FROM THIS TIME LAST YEAR INCLUDING A
43% DROP IN MOTOR VEHICLE THEFTS.
HOMICIDES IN OUR CITY ARE THE LOWEST THEY'VE BEEN IN SIX
DECADES. AND IT'S NOT JUST THE NATIONAL
TREND. CRIME IS DROPPING HERE FASTER
THAN IT IS IN OUR PEER CITIES. CHIEF SCOTT CAME TO THIS CITY
AS AN OUTSIDER AND AGAINST ALL ODDS HE WON THE RESPECT OF THE
CITY'S LEADERSHIP AND OUR MANY DIVERSE COMMUNITIES.
HE'S BEEN SUCCESSFUL ON EVERY METRICS CITY HALL COULD HAVE
SET FOR HIM. HE'S PROVEN THAT REFORM
AND SAFETY NEED NOT BE OPPOSITIONAL TO EACH OTHER.
DONE RIGHT. THEY ARE IN FACT COMPLIMENTARY
. CHIEF SCOTT, YOU'VE TRANSFORMED
OUR DEPARTMENT. YOU'VE LET IT THROUGH AN
UNPRECEDENTEDLY CHALLENGING PERIOD FOR POLICING NATIONALLY
AND LOCALLY. >> WE THANK YOU FOR YOUR
SERVICE TO SAN FRANCISCO. I COULD NOT BE PROUDER TO HONOR
YOU AGAIN HERE ONE LAST TIME FOR A JOB EXCEEDINGLY WELL DONE
. AND BEFORE YOU SPEAK MY
COLLEAGUES WANT TO TALK TO. >> SO SUPERVISOR DORSEY.
THANK YOU PRESIDENT MANDOLIN CHIEF.
>> I AGREE WITH THE BOARD PRESIDENT THAT THIS IS REALLY A
BITTERSWEET MOMENT. I JUST WANT TO SAY PERSONALLY
THAT I'M INCREDIBLY GRATEFUL THAT YOU GAVE ME A CHANCE
AND THEN I'M ALSO GRATEFUL THAT YOU GAVE ME A SECOND CHANCE.
>> I'LL NEVER FORGET IT. AND DURING THIS INCREDIBLY
DIFFICULT TIME FOR LAW ENFORCEMENT, MAYBE ONE OF THE
MOST DIFFICULT TIMES IN AT LEAST RECENT HISTORY A ONCE
IN A CENTURY PANDEMIC AND THE MURDER OF GEORGE FLOYD.
I JUST WATCHED YOU AGAIN AND AGAIN RISE TO THE MOMENT
WITH EQUANIMITY AND GRACE AND I LEARNED SO MUCH FROM YOU
AND I'M JUST SO GRATEFUL TO HAVE HAD THE OPPORTUNITY TO
WORK WITH YOU FOR A COUPLE OF YEARS.
THANK YOU. >> SUPERVISOR WALTON THANK YOU,
PRESIDENT MEADOW. AND I KNOW WE HONORED YOU
IN THIS CHAMBER A COUPLE OF WEEKS AGO AND THAT OF COURSE
WAS PRIOR TO KNOWING THAT YOU WERE RETIRING AND LEAVING US
HERE IN THIS CITY. >> BUT I DO JUST AGAIN WANT TO
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMITMENT TO SAN FRANCISCO FOR YOUR WORK
ON REFORM AND FOR COMING INTO A CITY AND REALLY WORKING HARD TO
MAKE CHANGE WHILE KEEPING THE CITY SAFE WHICH I KNOW IS
DEFINITELY A TASK. >> I DON'T AGREE WITH
SUPERVISOR OR PRESIDENT MANAGEMENT'S ASSESSMENT THAT
SAN FRANCISCO IS NOTORIOUSLY TOUGH ON COPS.
>> I WOULD ACTUALLY DISAGREE WITH THAT BUT I WILL SAY THIS
IS MOST DEFINITELY A CHALLENGING CITY TO LEAD IN AND
YOU HAVE DONE IT WITH GRACE. AND SO I WANT TO THANK YOU
AND APPRECIATE YOU AND JUST SAY I WISH YOU THE BEST IN ALL OF
YOUR FUTURE ENDEAVORS. >> THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU, PRESIDENT MELGAR.
THANK YOU, PRESIDENT MENDELSOHN.
CHIEF, YOU KNOW ALL OF MY COLLEAGUES ARE GOING TO TALK
ABOUT YOUR GREAT ACHIEVEMENTS AS A CHIEF AND THE U.S.
DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE RECOMMENDATIONS AND HOW YOU GOT
IT ALL DONE. I WANT TO TALK ABOUT WHAT AN
OUTSTANDING HUMAN BEING YOU ARE.
I THINK, YOU KNOW, PART OF WHAT MAKES US SUCCESSFUL
IN LEADERSHIP IS YOU KNOW THAT THE THINGS THAT WE DO FOR SURE
. BUT I THINK SOMETHING THAT
PEOPLE DON'T APPRECIATE AS MUCH AND SHOULD IS THAT TO BE A
LEADER OF THE STATUTE THAT YOU HAVE BEEN YOU NEED TO HAVE
OUTSTANDING HUMAN QUALITIES AND YOU REALLY DO.
SO YOU THOUGHTFULNESS YOUR EMPATHY, YOUR JUST WONDERFUL
HEART ARE SO IMPRESSIVE AND I FEEL A GREAT HONOR TO HAVE
GOTTEN TO KNOW YOU, TO TRAVEL WITH YOU, TO MEET YOUR MOM, TO
SEE WHERE YOU'RE FROM AND TO BE WITNESS TO SOME OF THE QUIETER
CONVERSATIONS THAT YOU HAVE HAD ABOUT DIFFICULT SUBJECTS WITH
YOUR COMMAND STAFF, WITH PEOPLE BEHIND THE SCENES WHICH REALLY
IMPRESSED ME IN TERMS OF THE QUALITY OF A HUMAN BEING THAT
YOU ARE. I AM SO PROFOUNDLY GRATEFUL
THAT YOU WERE WITH US AT THIS MOMENT.
I'M ALSO GRATEFUL FOR YOUR COMPETENCE AND YOUR SKILLS FOR
SURE. BUT JUST WHAT A WONDERFUL HUMAN
BEING YOU ARE AND HOW LUCKY WE ARE TO HAVE HAD YOU WALK WITH
US DURING THESE REALLY CRUCIAL MOMENTS IN THE HISTORY OF SAN
FRANCISCO AND THAT YOU HAVE TOUCHED SO MANY LIVES IN THIS
JOB IN JUST THROUGH YOUR PRESENCE, YOUR LEADERSHIP, YOUR
THOUGHTFULNESS AND YOUR JUST GREAT ABILITY.
>> THANK YOU, CHIEF. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR CHAN THANK YOU, PRESIDENT.
DOMAIN CHIEF I CONCUR WITH SUPERVISOR MACARTHUR.
>> WHAT A WONDERFUL HUMAN BEING YOU ARE FIRST AND THEN ALSO
CONCUR WITH SUPERVISOR WALTON THAT YOU HAVE BEEN CITY LEADERS
ONE OF THEM WITH SUCH A GRACE AND I WANT TO ALSO SAY THAT I
CANNOT THINK OF A MORE STRESSFUL JOB IN THIS CITY.
YOU KNOW, AMONG ALL THE CITY DEPARTMENTS OTHER THAN, YOU
KNOW, OUR FIRST RESPONDER, OUR FIRE AND POLICE IT JUST REALLY
INTENSE AND STRESSFUL AND YET I WANT TO SAY CHIEF SCOTT FOR
LAST HOWEVER LONG YOU KNOW, EVEN BEFORE I TOOK OFFICE AS A
SUPERVISOR I WANT TO SAY YOU HAVE BEEN A LEADER WAS SUCH A
KINDNESS AS AND I THINK THAT FOR ALL ELECTED LEADERS
AND CITY DEPARTMENT HEADS I DON'T THINK WE CAN ALL SAY THE
SAME IN THE MOMENT OF STRESS AND INTENSITY THAT WE CAN STILL
REMAIN AS KIND HUMAN BEING. BUT CHIEF SCOTT, I CAN SAY THAT
HAS ALWAYS BEEN TRUE ABOUT WHO YOU ARE EVEN IN THE MOST
STRESSFUL CIRCUMSTANCE. YOU HAVE BEEN NOTHING BUT KIND
AND I THINK THAT IS AMAZING AND THAT REALLY DEMONSTRATE
CHARACTER FOR YOU AS AS A HUMAN BEING AND THAT LIKE I HAVE
TREMENDOUS RESPECT FOR YOU BECAUSE OF THAT AND I KNOW THAT
YOUR POLY IT'S LIKE MORE RELAX AS YOU'RE MOVING ON TO YOUR
NEXT POST. NONETHELESS THAT I THINK THAT
THEY'RE VERY LUCKY TO HAVE YOU AS THEIR LEADER WHATEVER THAT
YOU'RE GOING TO DO NEXT. AND YOU KNOW, I THINK IT'S
GOING TO BE REALLY LUCKY TO HAVE YOU BACK BUT WE'RE GOING
TO MISS YOU AND FOR ALL THAT YOU HAVE ACCOMPLISHED IN SAN
FRANCISCO, I AM SO GRATEFUL. >> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
THANK YOU. >> SUPERVISOR SUPERVISOR
AND GARCIA, I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR YOUR SERVICE.
I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR BEING A LEADER IN REFORM AND JUST BEING
A GREAT OVERALL PERSON. YOU KNOW YOU HAVE DONE MORE
WITH LESS. YOU HAVE HANDLED EVERY
CHALLENGE THIS CITY AND OUR SOCIETY HAS THROWN AT YOU.
YOU HAVE SHOWN HOW THE SAN FRANCISCO POLICE DEPARTMENT CAN
BE AN HONORABLE PLACE, HOW POLICE OFFICERS CAN BE
HONORABLE. I KNOW AS WE TRY TO GET FULL
STAFFING WE WANT YOUNG PEOPLE TO WANT TO BE OFFICERS AND I
THINK THEY JUST NEED TO LOOK AT BILL SCOTT AND SEE THAT EXAMPLE
AND THEN PEOPLE WILL WANT TO FOLLOW IN YOUR FOOTSTEPS.
SO THANK YOU FOR SHOWING US WHAT IS POSSIBLE AND WHAT OUR
POLICE DEPARTMENT CAN BE. AND I'M HOPEFUL FOR OUR FUTURE
BECAUSE OF YOUR LEADERSHIP. SO THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISING AREA SUPERVISOR
CHEN. >> THANK YOU, PRESIDENT.
CHIEF SCOTT, I WANT TO THANK YOU THANK YOU FOR YOUR
LEADERSHIP AND I ALSO WANT TO THANK YOU FOR YOUR ATTENTION TO
THIS JUST 11 IN THE SHORT MONTH A COUPLE OF MONTHS THAT WE WORK
TOGETHER. >> YOU'VE CAME TO OUR DISTRICT
TO TALK ABOUT THE BLESSING SCAM.
WE HAVE DONE MUCH WALK TOGETHER SO I REALLY APPRECIATE
AND ENJOYED IT ALL THE WORK THAT WE'D DONE TOGETHER IN THE
LAST COUPLE OF MONTHS AND YOU WILL BE MISSED.
>> I REALLY WANT TO WISH YOU ALL THE BEST IN THE FUTURE
ENDEAVOR. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR CHEN.
>> SUPERVISOR SHERYL G. SCOTT THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR
YOUR SERVICE. YOU'VE LEFT THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT THAT IS STRONGER THAN WHEN YOU CAME AND I THINK
THERE'S NO BETTER ACCOMPLISHMENT AND AS IS SAN
FRANCISCO STRONGER FOR YOUR SERVICE.
>> THANK YOU. BUT I ALSO WANT TO THANK YOUR
FAMILY FOR ALLOWING YOU TO DO THIS WORK AND GIVING YOU TO US
IN MANY WAYS IS AN HONOR TO MEET THEM EARLIER IS REALLY AN
HONOR TO BE ABLE TO MEET YOUR SON WHICH WAS A REAL JOY FOR
ME. SO THANK YOU.
BUT MORE THANK YOU TO THEM FOR FOR ALLOWING THIS AND ALL THE
BEST FOR REALLY EXCITED TO SEE WHAT YOU ACCOMPLISH IN L.A.
THANK YOU SUPERVISOR SHERYL SUPERVISOR FIELDER THANKS
PRESIDENT GENTLEMAN. >> CHIEF, I KNOW WE DIDN'T HAVE
TOO MUCH TIME OVERLAPPING BUT I JUST WANT TO THANK YOU FOR
STEPPING UP WHEN OUR CITY WAS REAFFIRMING OUR COMMITMENT TO
SANCTUARY CITY FOR OUR IMMIGRANT COMMUNITY AND YOU
KNOW, WE'RE ON THE PHONE TRYING TO HASH OUT WHAT WAS TRUE, WHAT
WAS RUMOR WHEN IT BECAME WHEN IT CAME TO ICE PRESENCE.
AND SO I JUST WANT TO THANK YOU FOR THAT.
IT'S IMPORTANT THAT THE CITY KNOWS AND OUR IMMIGRANT FAMILY
AND FRIENDS KNOW THAT THEIR POLICE CHIEF IS BEHIND THEM.
SO I JUST WANT TO THANK YOU FOR THAT AND IT'S CLEAR THAT YOU
DON'T SEE YOURSELF AS AS SEPARATE FROM THE COMMUNITY
AND YOU REALLY VALUE BEING WITH THE COMMUNITY WALKING ALONGSIDE
FOLKS ON THE GROUND AND I THINK THAT IS REALLY CLEAR AND THE
LATINO COMMUNITY THAT YOU HAVE MADE INROADS WITH OVER THE
SEVERAL YEARS AND SO I JUST WANT TO THANK YOU FOR THAT
AND WISH YOU BEST OF LUCK. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR FIELD SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD CHIEF SCOTT, I JUST
WANT TO THANK YOU AGAIN FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP OVER THE LAST
SEVERAL YEARS BUT SPECIFICALLY FOR LEADING WITH BOTH
INNOVATION AND COLLABORATION AND UNDERSTANDING THAT THE TWO
GO HAND IN HAND AT THE MAYOR'S HONORING OF YOU YOU COMMENTED
HOW THERE IS DEPARTMENT HEADS COMING TO HONOR THE CHIEF THAT
SPEAKS TO YOU RECOGNIZING THAT EVERYONE NEEDS TO WORK TOGETHER
AND I THINK THERE'S NO BETTER REPRESENTATION OF THAT.
WHEN YOU INITIATED THE DMCC DRUG MARKET AGENCY COORDINATION
CENTER WHICH WAS REALLY AN INTERAGENCY EFFORT THAT AS A PD
LED IN PARTNERSHIP WITH PUBLIC HEALTH THE DA'S OFFICE
SHERIFF'S OFFICE, PUBLIC WORKS AND I THINK THE TENDERLOIN HAS
BENEFITED SO MUCH FROM THE INITIATIVES AND THE FOUNDATIONS
THAT YOU LED IN COLLABORATION WITH THE REST OF THE CITY.
AND NOW AS WE'RE SEEING THE TENDERLOIN ON THE UPSWING, IT
IS REALLY DUE TO YOUR EFFORT AND YOUR LEADERSHIP THAT THAT
FOUNDATION HAS BEEN PUT IN PLACE THAT WE CAN BENEFIT
FROM THE SUCCESS AND YOUR EFFORT IN SETTING UP THAT
FOUNDATION FOR AS YOU LEAVE. BUT ALSO I WANTED TO COMMEND
YOU ON THE CULTURE THAT YOU CREATED WITHIN THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT. I SEE IT EVERY DAY IN ALL THREE
STATIONS THAT ARE IN DISTRICT FIVE BUT SPECIFICALLY IN THE
TENDERLOIN AND WHERE I SEE BEAT OFFICERS AND OFFICERS ENGAGING
IN THE COMMUNITY AND RECOGNIZING THEIR
RESPONSIBILITY TO ENGAGE WITH A VARIETY OF COMMUNITIES
AND DEMOGRAPHICS AND THAT AGAIN I BELIEVE IS IS DUE TO YOUR
LEADERSHIP OF COLLABORATION WITHIN COMMUNITY BUT ALSO
ACROSS DEPARTMENTS. AND WE'RE SEEING THE RESULTS OF
THAT DUE TO YOUR LEADERSHIP. SO THANK YOU AGAIN FOR ALL
YOU'VE DONE. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR MEMO SUPERVISOR SARTOR ALL RIGHT CHIEF, I
PROMISE TO BE THE LAST ONE TO SPEAK BECAUSE THERE'S NO MORE
HE GOT 11 OUT OF 11 I YOU KNOW BEING NEW TO THIS JOB I REGRET
WE DIDN'T HAVE A CHANCE TO TO WORK LONGER TOGETHER.
BUT YOU KNOW THROUGH THE YEARS I OBSERVED YOUR LEADERSHIP FROM
AFAR, YOU KNOW, WHETHER THAT WAS IN DIFFICULT TOWN HALL
MEETINGS, WHETHER THAT WAS ON ALL THE ZOOM WEBINARS THROUGH
THE YEARS, WHETHER THAT WAS ON THE NEWS AND YOU KNOW SO JUST
THESE SHORT FEW MONTHS IT WAS REALLY, YOU KNOW, SPECIAL TO
SEE THAT UP FRONT AND ALL OF THE WORK THAT YOU'VE DONE AS
OTHERS HAVE EXPRESSED IS EXTRAORDINARY.
BUT I THINK MORE SO THAN THAT IS GOING TO BE THE LEGACY THAT
YOU LEAVE. IT'S GOING TO BE THE SHOES THAT
NEED TO BE FILLED AND I THINK THAT'S GOING TO BE BE YOUR
GREATEST LEGACY IS THAT THAT CULTURE OF LEADERSHIP AND THE
CULTURE OF OF CHANGING THOUSANDS AND THOUSANDS OF OF
TEAM MEMBERS THAT YOU WORKED WITH THROUGH THE YEARS.
SO I APPRECIATE ALL YOUR SERVICE AND I WISH YOU AND YOUR
FAMILY ALL THE BEST. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR SOLDIER THAT'S THE CREW CHIEF SCOTT THE FLOOR IS
YOURS. >> THANK YOU.
STARTING WITH PRESIDENT MADAM AND TO ALL OF OUR SUPERVISORS
EARS AND TO MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC IN THE DEPARTMENT.
YOU KNOW NONE OF THIS HAPPENS IN A VACUUM AND IT'S BEEN IT'S
BEEN A GREAT EIGHT YEARS. >> SO THERE'S SO MANY THINGS TO
SAY HERE. I JUST WANT TO MAKE IT SIMPLE.
I CAN POINT OUT SO MANY PEOPLE THAT I WORK WITH BOTH ON AN
INDIVIDUAL BASIS AND BOARD MEMBERS HERE THAT ARE HERE THAT
ARE NOT HERE PRESENT AND PAST COMMUNITY MEMBERS.
>> I'M LOOKING AT REVEREND BROWN OVER THERE THAT HAVE
SUPPORTED AND BEEN WITH US THROUGH THICK AND THIN AND WHEN
I LOOK BACK AT ALL THE PEOPLE THAT ARE HERE TO SUPPORT THIS
MOMENT, IT TOUCHED ME A LITTLE BIT.
BUT I WANT TO SAY THANK YOU FIRST OF ALL TO MY WIFE AND MY
SON WHO ARE HERE BECAUSE I WOULDN'T BE HERE WITHOUT THEM.
TO ALL THE MEMBERS OF THE SPEEDY THEY DO THE WORK
AND IT'S AN HONOR TO LEAD. IT IS AN HONOR TO LEAD THIS
DEPARTMENT. BUT THEY DO THE WORK AND SO I
AM GRATEFUL FOR THEM. YOU KNOW THE CITY IS SPECIAL
AND IT'S A PLACE THAT I ALWAYS WANTED TO LIVE.
SO HAVING THE HONOR TO COME HERE AS THE CHIEF AND SERVE FOR
EIGHT YEARS HAS REALLY BEEN A HIGHLIGHT OF MY LIFE AND YEAH,
WE HAVE OUR CHALLENGES, WE HAVE OUR DIFFICULTIES BUT IT'S AN
EASY CITY TO LOVE AND I LOVE THE CITY FOR THOSE PEOPLE THAT
KNOW ME WAY BEFORE I GOT HERE. SO I'M JUST GRATEFUL FOR
EVERYBODY THAT HAVE BEEN A PART OF THIS JOURNEY.
YOU HAVE SEEN THE LAST OF ME MAYBE IN THIS JOB YOU'VE SEEN
IT LAST YEAR BUT YOU HAVEN'T SEEN THE LAST OF ME BECAUSE I
DO HAVE ROOTS HERE NOW AND I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO COMING BACK
AND ACTUALLY HAVING TIME TO ENJOY THE BEAUTY OF THE CITY
WHEN I'M NOT WORKING. AND SO I JUST WANT TO AGAIN SAY
THANK YOU TO EVERYBODY SO MANY MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC THAT ARE
HERE SORRY I CRACKED UP A LITTLE BIT UP HERE BUT IT'S AN
EMOTIONAL MOMENT FOR ME BECAUSE IT IS BITTERSWEET AS MUCH AS I
RELISH THE OPPORTUNITY TO BUILD A NEW POLICE DEPARTMENT
AND REALLY THAT'S THE THING THAT THAT DID IT FOR ME IS TO
TAKE EVERYTHING THAT I'VE LEARNED HERE AND APPLY IT TO A
NEW DEPARTMENT AND TRY TO BUILD THE DEPARTMENT.
THAT'S RIGHT. AND THAT DOES THE RIGHT THING
AND TREATS PEOPLE RIGHT. AND IT'S THE SAME THING THAT WE
DID HERE. SO SAN FRANCISCO WILL BE A PART
OF MY DNA FOREVER MORE AND I GUARANTEE YOU OUGHT TO BE A
PART OF THE DNA OF THIS POLICE DEPARTMENT THAT I'VE BEEN
TASKED TO BUILD. SO AGAIN, I WANT TO THANK YOU
ALL AND IT'S BEEN AN HONOR TO BE HERE AS CHIEF OF POLICE.
THANK YOU. >> CHIEF, I'M GOING TO ASK YOU
TO COME IN TO THE WELL
,WE MISSED YOU TOO. I ALWAYS WANTED I'VE ALWAYS
WONDERED WHAT YOU ALWAYS THOUGHT IN SERVICE WHEN THOSE
SERVING TYPICALLY ELEVATED FOR A SALARY.
>> OH, RIGHT. NEXT UP WE HAVE FROM DISTRICT
NINE SUPERVISOR FIELDER. ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU PRESIDENT TODAY WELL WELL, ACTUALLY LET'S WAIT A
SECOND. >> YES, SORRY.
>> SUPERVISOR FIELDER THANK YOU .
I WANT TO CALL UP A VERY SPECIAL PERSON ALSO AND AS OF
PD CAPTAIN JOHANSEN, PLEASE COME TO THE PODIUM.
>> IT IS MY HONOR TO RECOGNIZE CAPTAIN LISA JOHANSSON OF THE
AS OF PETERS MISSION STATION. CAPTAIN JOHANSSON IS NOT JUST A
POLICE CAPTAIN. SHE IS A PART OF OUR COMMUNITY
RAISED IN THE VERY HEART OF THE MISSION DISTRICT SHAPED BY ITS
CULTURE, ITS RESILIENCE AND DIVERSITY.
>> SHE KNOWS THESE STREETS NOT JUST AS PATROL ROUTES BUT AS
THE PLACES WHERE SHE GREW UP. >> SHE HAS A STORY AND A
CONNECTION TO NOT JUST THE STREETS AND THE BUILDINGS BUT
TO THE PEOPLE IN THEM. SINCE TAKING COMMAND AT MISSION
STATION STILL UNDER A YEAR AGO ,CAPTAIN JOHANSSON HAS DONE
SOMETHING TRULY REMARKABLE. AFTER DECADES OF ISSUES SHE
FINALLY GOT AIR CONDITIONING INSTALLED AT THE MISSION POLICE
STATION. NO, BUT IN ALL SERIOUSNESS, SHE
HAS DONE SOMETHING THAT FEW CAPTAINS IN THE MISSION COULD.
SHE HAS BROUGHT PEOPLE TOGETHER ALL PEOPLE LONGTIME RESIDENTS,
NEWER FOLKS, IMMIGRANT FAMILIES, LOCAL BUSINESS OWNERS
,YOUTH YOUTH LEADERS AND SENIORS.
>> SHE IS ABOUT SERVING JUST A FEW PEOPLE SHE SHE IS ABOUT
SERVING ALL PEOPLE. SHE HAS MADE EVERY CONSTITUENT
NO MATTER THEIR BACKGROUND FEEL SEEN, HEARD AND PROTECTED.
>> SHE HAS SHOWN THAT SAFETY AND TRUST GO HAND IN HAND IN A
DISTRICT AS STORIED AND DIVERSE AS THE MISSION WHETHER HOSTING
COMMUNITY MEETINGS, ATTENDING NEIGHBORHOOD EVENTS NOT JUST
IN UNIFORM BUT AS A COMMUNITY PARTNER OR CREATING NEW SPACES
FOR DIALOG AND HEALING. >> CAPTAIN JOHANSSON HAS LED
WITH HUMILITY AND HEART. SHE MAY BE A SHARP SHOOTER BUT
SHE ALSO DEEPLY CARES. >> WHEN MISSION NEIGHBORHOOD
CENTER WAS OPENING UP A NEW DAYCARE CENTER AT THE SITE OF A
FORMER POLICE STATION, SHE WAS THERE WHEN AT THE BEGINNING OF
THE YEAR OUR COMMUNITY WAS INUNDATED WITH REPORTS
AND CONCERNS ABOUT IMMIGRATION ENFORCEMENT.
>> SHE WAS THERE BEING FROM THE MISSION AND BEING A SEASONED AS
OF PD OFFICER WHO HAS RISEN THROUGH THE RANKS.
SHE STRADDLES TWO WORLDS ALWAYS AND HAS SEEN AND EXPERIENCED
THINGS MOST OF US NEVER WILL. >> ALL WITH AN UNMATCHED
PROFESSIONALISM, DUTIFUL NESS AND A SENSE OF HUMOR.
>> WE COULD NOT HAVE ASKED FOR A BETTER CAPTAIN.
>> TRULY WE COULD NOT HAVE ASKED FOR A BETTER LEADER.
SUPERVISOR FIELD CAN I GET YOU TO STOP FOR A SECOND?
SO HERE'S THE THING. THESE MEETINGS WILL NOT WORK IF
MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC ARE BURSTING OUT.
AND I UNDERSTAND THAT FOLKS HAVE A LOT OF STUFF THEY WANT
TO SAY. >> THAT'S WHAT PUBLIC COMMENT
IS FOR. BUT BUT WE ARE NOT GOING TO BE
ABLE TO GO FORWARD WITH THIS MEETING IF PEOPLE ARE CALLING
OUT FROM THE AUDIENCE. >> SUPERVISOR FIELDING PERFECT
EXAMPLE. >> WE COULD HAVE NOT HAVE ASKED
FOR A BETTER CAPTAIN. >> WE COULD NOT HAVE ASKED FOR
A BETTER LEADER WHOSE DEEP BELIEF IN THE POTENTIAL OF THE
MISSION DISTRICT AND THE PEOPLE WHO CALL IT HOME GUIDES HER
WORK AND RESPONSIBILITY TO ITS PEOPLE EVERY DAY.
NO MATTER WHAT CRIES SHE GETS NO MATTER HOW MUCH SHE'S YELLED
AT HER. AND I SHARE A LOT OF THIS THIS
TOGETHER AND ON BEHALF OF THE SAN FRANCISCO SUPERVISORS I
JUST WANT TO EXTEND MY DEEPEST GRATITUDE TO CAPTAIN JOHANSSON
WITH ALL OUR LOVE AND APPRECIATION.
THANK YOU SO MUCH. >> THANK YOU SO THE SUPERVISOR
FIELD OVER FOR I'M PUTTING MYSELF IN THE QUEUE.
>> IT IS A MEASURE OF THE WISDOM AND SAVVY OF MY DISTRICT
NINE COLLEAGUE THAT SHE HAS BEATEN ME TO IT TO RECOGNIZING
CAPTAIN JOHANSON BUT I AM SO GRATEFUL AS WELL FOR YOUR
AMAZING SERVICE AND JUST LIKE IT'S BEEN LIKE A YEAR I THINK
ABOUT. >> AND MISSION STATION I DON'T
KNOW IF THERE'S AN EASY STATION BUT I THINK MISSION MIGHT BE
AMONG THE MOST DIFFICULT CHALLENGING THERE ARE YOU KNOW
THE DIVERSITY OF NEEDS AND DEMANDS COMING FROM FROM
THE VARIOUS COMMUNITIES THAT THAT MISSION STATION WORKS WITH
ARE HARD TO KEEP TRACK OF AND BALANCE.
AND I KNOW WE'RE ALL PRESSING FOR MORE AND DIFFERENCE
AND SENDING A LOT OF DIFFERENT SIGNALS AND I THINK THAT THE
CAPTAIN JUST ALSO I AGREE WITH MY DISTRICT NINE COLLEAGUE JUST
DOES A PHENOMENAL JOB. SO THANK YOU AND TO EVERYONE AT
MISSION STATION A LOT YOU KNOW, ABUNDANT THANKS AND THANK YOU
SUPERVISOR FIELDER FOR DOING THIS COMBINATION AND NOW YOU
CAN TALK AND COUNT AND DO MY BEST NOT TO CRY SO I'M
INCREDIBLY GRATEFUL TO ACCEPT THE CERTIFICATE FROM THE BOARD
OF SUPERVISORS AND I WANT TO ESPECIALLY THANKS FOR VISOR
JACKIE FELDER FOR THIS THOUGHTFUL RECOGNITION.
IT TRULY MEANS A LOT NOT JUST TO ME BUT TO THE ENTIRE TEAM
AND FAMILY AT MISSION STATION WHO SHOW UP EVERY DAY WITH
HEART, GRIT AND A DEEP COMMITMENT TO THE PEOPLE OF THE
MISSION. SERVING THE COMMUNITY HAS BEEN
ONE OF THE MOST MEANINGFUL CHAPTERS OF MY CAREER AS IT IS
TRULY ME AND MY LIFE COME FULL CIRCLE THE RELATIONSHIPS WE
BUILT WITH RESIDENTS, BUSINESS OWNERS, COMMUNITY LEADERS
AND EACH OTHER ARE WHAT MAKE THE WORK NOT ONLY POSSIBLE BUT
WORTH DOING. >> I'VE LEARNED SO MUCH FROM
THIS DISTRICT AND FROM THE PEOPLE WHO CALL IT HOME.
THANK YOU FOR THIS HONOR. I'M PROUD TO ACCEPT IT AND EVEN
MORE PROUD TO CONTINUE WALKING ALONGSIDE ALL OF YOU AS WE WORK
TOWARD A SAFER AND MORE JUST SAN FRANCISCO.
>> AND I WANT TO TAKE THIS MOMENT TO THANK THE CHIEF FOR
TEACHING ME HOW TO LEAD WITH LOVE SAFER AND MORE JUST OKAY.
OVER 300 I'M NOT GOING I JOKE I'M A JOKE.
OKAY. OKAY COOL.
YEAH. AND IT'S.
I BET YOU I CAN NEVER KILL FEDERAL.
YOU SPEND AN HOUR RECOGNIZING THESE OFFICERS THAT EARN HALF
$1 MILLION A YEAR. >> WHAT DO YOU GET?
MURDER. ALL RIGHT.
WITH THANKS TO OUR DEPUTY SHERIFFS DISTRICT 11 SUPERVISOR
CHEN THANK YOU, PRESIDENT. HAPPY PRIME AND EVERYBODY
AND GOOD AFTERNOON TODAY IT'S MY GREAT HONOR TO HONOR THE
CHICKEN LAUNCH A LOCAL FOOD AND DRINK ESTABLISHMENT
IN DISTRICT 11 IT IT'S A LGBTQ OWNED LOCAL HANGOUT SPOT AND A
PROJECT OF LOVE FROM TWO CO-OWNERS WHICH ARE LOCAL
ZAVALA AND JEFF SCOTT AS JEFF SCOTT RICH AND JEFF ARE PAO
IMMIGRANTS AND MEMBER OF OUT OF THE LGBTQ COMMUNITY WHO HAVE
CALLED SAN FRANCISCO HOME SAN FRANCISCO HOME SINCE THE 2000
RICHER CAME TO SAN FRANCISCO FROM VENICE OF VENICE BOOLA
AND HE IS A LICENSED THERAPIST WHO HAS WORKED IN IN THE
PRIVATE SECTOR AND WITH NONPROFIT AGENCIES IN THE BAY
AREA FOR THE LAST 20 YEARS. SO HE IS EXACTLY WHO WE WANT TO
BE OUR BARTENDER IS AN EXPERIENCED IT LISTENING EAR
WHO HAS SUPPORTED YOU FROM ACROSS THE COUNTER.
>> JEFFREY EMIGRATED FROM AUSTRALIA AND HAS YEARS OF
EXPERIENCE WORKING WITH WINE AND IN FOOD PRODUCTION
IN ANIMATION. >> RICH AND JEFF BOTH OWN HOMES
IN THE MISSION TERRACE NEIGHBORHOOD IN DISTRICT 11
AND THEY LOVE HOSTING AND ENTER ENTERTAINING THEIR FRIENDS
AND FAMILIES. AND AS WE KNOW IN 2020 THE
BEGINNING OF COVID 19 PANDEMIC DEEPLY ISOLATED MANY OF US RICH
AND JEFF'S SAW AND FELT THE ISOLATION AND WANTED TO CREATE
A SPACE WHERE PEOPLE CAN LEARN ABOUT AND APPRECIATE WINE
AND CHECK IN WITH EACH OTHER AS AN ANTIDOTE TO PANDEMIC BLUES.
>> THEY TOOK COMMISSIONS TO ACTION AND OPENED IT THE CHECK
IN LAUNCH IN SEPTEMBER 2021 BRING IN THEIR PASSION AS HOSTS
TO THE WIDER COMMUNITY. >> THEY NEIGHBORS HAVE EMBRACED
DID THE SPACE AND PUT ON SO MANY EVENTS FOR PEOPLE TO
CONNECT AND CELEBRATE FROM LIVE MUSIC MICHELIN STYLE FOOD
HALLOWEEN PARTY HOLLY PIE PARTIES KNITTING GROUPS FOR MOM
CHESS GROUPS FOR THAT AND MOTHER'S DAY CELEBRATION
THE TRACK AND THE LIST GOES ON AND THE CHECK IN LAUNCH IT'S
INCREDIBLY WARM INVITING AND GRASSROOTS ON TOP OF THAT
RICH MOM IT'S A BELOVED FIXTURE AT THE LAUNCH AS WELL
WELCOMING EVERYONE TO THE SPACE, MAKING IT FEEL MORE LIKE
A BELOVED COMMUNITY CENTER WHERE WE CAN BE OUR FULL SELF
AND BRINGING OUR IDEAS TO LIFE DURING THE PANDEMIC.
AFTER A DEAR FRIEND OF MINE PASSED AWAY, THE CHECK
IN LAUNCH WAS A SAFE HEALING SPACE FOR ME AND MY FRIENDS TO
GRIEVE, TO CRY AND TO DANCE. >> ALL IN ALL THE CHECK
IN LAUNCH IS AN EXTRAORDINARY SAFE HAVEN ON AN OTHERWISE
ORDINARY STREET CORNER ON OCEAN AVENUE AND OUR SAKE AND OUR
STEGALL AVENUE IN A TIME OF RISING HATE AND DIVISION WE
PROUDLY CELEBRATE PRIDE MONTH IN SAN FRANCISCO A MONTH THAT
HONORS THE 1969 STONEWALL RIOTS A PIVOTAL MOVEMENT IN THE GAY
RIGHTS MOVEMENT THAT IS ACTIVE RESISTANCE AGAINST HATE AND TO
FIGHT FOR LOVE AND LIBERATIONS EVERY DAY.
>> IT'S ABOUT LOVE AT THE CHECK IN LAUNCH BECAUSE OWNERS RICH
AND JEFF KNOW THAT WHAT IT TAKES TO ACTIVELY ACTIVELY
CULTIVATE BELONGING AND INCLUSIONS CHAIRS THE CHECK
IN LAUNCH AND HAPPY PRIDE MONTH.
>> THANK YOU JEFF AND THANK YOU RICH GOOD AFTERNOON.
>> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHAN AND THANK YOU ALL FOR YOUR TIME
THIS AFTERNOON. SO WE JUST WANTED TO WORK A
LITTLE BIT ON THE INTRODUCTION THAT SUPERVISOR CHEN GAVE US.
SO WHERE THE CHICKEN LOUNGE WERE AT 201 OCEAN AVENUE IN SAN
FRANCISCO'S MISSION TERRACE NEIGHBORHOOD FOR US THE CHECK
IN IS MORE ABOUT WINE AND COCKTAILS.
>> IT'S ABOUT CONNECTION, CONVERSATION, PASSION
AND LEARNING ABOUT THE WORLD THROUGH A LOCAL PERSPECTIVE
WHERE A PLACE WHERE GUESTS CAN ESTABLISH A PERSONAL CONNECTION
AND GET TO KNOW THEIR NEIGHBORS.
WE OPENED DURING THE COVID PANDEMIC IN SEPTEMBER 2021
STARTING WITH JUST A BEER AND WINE LICENSE BUT WE WERE
ABLE TO HAVE THE OPPORTUNITY TO EXPAND TO USE THE NEIGHBORHOOD
FOR LIQUOR LICENSES AND SO WE WERE ABLE TO EXPAND OUR
SERVICES IN MARCH OF 2023. TODAY WE OFFER SMALL BITES
INCLUDING CHEESE PLATES, FLATBREAD, PIZZAS, LASAGNA
AND VENEZUELAN TO KENYANS MADE BY RICH'S MOM AND ALONGSIDE OUR
ALL ALONGSIDE OUR WINE, BEER AND COCKTAIL SELECTION.
BUT WE'VE ALSO BECOME A HUB FOR THE NEIGHBORHOOD WITH STREET
ACTIVATIONS PARTNERING WITH LOCAL ORGANIZATIONS SUCH AS
EXCELSIOR ACTION GROUP, THE NEW MISSION TERRACE NEIGHBORHOOD
IMPROVEMENT ASSOCIATION AND AND WE'VE HOSTED A SERIES OF
ACTIVATIONS CALLED ALFRESCO OUTDOORS AND THESE HAVE
INCLUDED COMMUNITY PASTA DINNERS THE THE HALLOWEEN BLOCK
PARTY, THE DIWALI AND HOLI THAT SUPERVISOR CHEN MENTIONED.
AND COMING UP WILL BE HOSTING ANOTHER PRIDE BLOCK PARTY WE'VE
ALWAYS IMAGINED THE CHECK IN AS A SPACE THAT BRINGS PEOPLE
TOGETHER AND WE HOPE THAT WE'VE CREATED A SPOT THAT FEELS
WELCOME TO ALL. THANK YOU TO SUPERVISOR CHEN
FOR THIS HONOR. THANK YOU ALSO TO DAVID HOOPER
,LAURA LOUGHBOROUGH AND MICHELLE MCGEE WHO ARE SOME
OF OUR NEIGHBORHOOD SUPPORTERS HERE TODAY AND WE WANT TO
INVITE EVERYBODY TO COME ALONG ON JUNE 22ND TO OUR NEXT
NEIGHBORHOOD BLOCK PARTY FOR PRIDE.
IT'LL BE AT 2:00 ON THE SUNDAY AFTERNOON.
THANK YOU ALL FOR YOUR TIME. >> WE'RE VERY HUMBLED BY THIS.
THANK YOU
. >> DISTRICT ONE SUPERVISOR JAN
THANK YOU PRESIDENT BENJAMIN. >> COLLEAGUES THEN THANKS
HONOREE IS SOMEONE WHO IS A CHAMPION FOR COMMUNITY POLICING
AND HAS WORKED ON THE GROUND FOR ALMOST 30 YEARS OFTEN
ALONGSIDE WITH COMMUNITY LEADERS, VICTIMS AND POLICE
OFFICERS IN SHAPING A MODEL OF COLLECTIVE CARE AND JUSTICE
IN PROMOTING JUSTICE AND PROMOTING PUBLIC SAFETY
AND CRIMINAL JUSTICE IN A JOINT EFFORT WITH SUPERVISOR BRIAN
CHEN IT IS MY PLEASURE TO RECOGNIZE MY OLD BOSS.
REALLY IT'S SOMEONE WHO HAS TAUGHT ME SO MUCH ABOUT
COMMUNITY BUILDING AND PUBLIC SAFETY AND I'M IT'S MY
PRIVILEGE TO BE ABLE TO ALSO CALL HIM MY FRIEND MR. MICHAEL
WONG FOR HIS SERVICE TO SAN FRANCISCO WORKING CLASS
FAMILIES AT RISK YOUTH, IMMIGRANTS AND SURVIVORS OF
VIOLENCE FOR THE PAST THREE DECADES.
>> I WANT TO SAY MY GO IS CURRENTLY THE SENIOR PROGRAM
DIRECTOR AT THE COMMUNITY YOUTH CENTER CIC BUT MANY OF US WERE
ALREADY KNOWING HIM FOR A VERY ,VERY LONG TIME WAY BEFORE HIS
TIME AS CIC. YOU KNOW IF YOU KNOW CIC THEN
YOU KNOW THAT IT IS ONE OF THE LEADING ORGANIZATIONS IN CITY
FOCUS ON YOUTH EMPOWERMENT COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT BUT THEY
ALSO ARE ONE OF THE LEADING ORGANIZATIONS THAT COORDINATE
AND PROVIDE CULTURALLY RESPONSIVE DIRECT SUPPORT
VICTIM ADVOCACY AND CROSS RACIAL SOLIDARITY AND EDUCATION
WORK. I THINK SUPERVISOR WALTON KNOWS
THAT AND PARTICULARLY MANY OF THE CIC PROGRAMS SERVE
NON-ENGLISH SPEAKING SURVIVORS OF VIOLENCE WHO OTHERWISE WOULD
HAVE DIFFICULTIES NAVIGATING THROUGH THE COMPLEX SYSTEM OF
THE CRIMINAL JUSTICE SYSTEM. MICHAEL LAID THE FOUNDATION OF
WORK IN SHAPING SO MUCH OF THE VICTIM SERVICES THAT WE SEE
IN THE COMMUNITY TODAY AND IT'S ALSO SOMEONE WHO I LEARNED FROM
ABOUT VICTIM SERVICES AND CRIMINAL JUSTICE.
MICHAEL HAS BEEN A FRONTLINE WORKER AND TRUSTED COMMUNITY
CONNECTOR IN SOME OF THE CITY'S MOST PROMINENT SOCIAL SERVICES
INSTITUTIONS INCLUDING EIGHT YEARS AS SAN FRANCISCO
NEIGHBORHOOD SAFETY PARTNERSHIP .
THAT'S WHERE I LEARNED FROM HIM AND TEN YEARS AT THE AMERICAN
RED CROSS AND MORE THAN A DECADE AT THE COMMUNITY YOUTH
CENTER. MICHAEL HELPED PIONEERED A
HOLISTIC SUPPORT SERVICE MODEL FOR ASIAN-AMERICAN VICTIMS OF
VIOLENCE, PROVIDING THEM THE COUNSELING, LEGAL SUPPORT
AND FINANCIAL ASSISTANCE IMMEDIATELY AT THE FIRST POINT
OF CONTACT JUST IN THE LAST FOUR YEARS AS CIC HE PERSONALLY
DELIVERED THESE COORDINATED SERVICES TO OVER 330
INDIVIDUALS FROM ACROSS THE CITY.
IN 2019 MICHAEL CO-FOUNDED THE COALITION FOR COMMUNITY SAFETY
AND JUSTICE SJ WHICH WAS ESTABLISHED IN DIRECT RESPONSE
TO THE INCREASED VIOLENCE AGAINST THE ASIAN AMERICAN
COMMUNITY AND THE NEED TO PROMOTE LONG LASTING HEALING
FOR TRAUMA SURVIVORS AND THE COMMUNITY FOR FROM GENERATIONAL
HARM. HE FORGED UNPRECEDENTED
CROSS-RACIAL SOLIDARITY EFFORTS PARTICULARLY BETWEEN THE
CHINESE-AMERICAN AND THE BLACK AMERICAN COMMUNITIES THROUGH
STORYTELLING DIALOG AND SHARE CULTURAL EVENTS.
IN 2024 ALONE, MICHAEL LED LARGE SCALE ENGAGEMENT EFFORTS
WHICH EQUATED TO 165 SAFETY WORKSHOP 42 COMMUNITY EVENTS
AND OUTREACH OPPORTUNITIES THAT REACH OVER 34,000 SAN
FRANCISCANS. MICHAEL TRULY EMBODIES THE
VALUES OF EQUITY, DIGNITY AND HEALING.
HE CONTINUES TO SERVE AS A TRUSTED BRIDGE BUILDER AND A
ROLE MODEL FOR MANY EMERGING YOUNG LEADERS INCLUDING THE
8000 YANG CIC I WOULD SAY INCLUDING THE 800 800 OR 8000
YOU CIC SERVES SORRY I KNOW THAT MICHAEL BROUGHT HIS FAMILY
WITH HIM TODAY. THIS RECOGNITION IS AS MUCH AS
MICHAEL'S IT IS THEIRS. THANK YOU.
ANNA HIS WIFE AND SON JASON FOR SHARING MICHAEL WITH THE
COMMUNITY AND THANK YOU MICHAEL.
I SEE THAT ALSO MY COLLEAGUES WANT TO SAY A FEW WORDS BUT I
JUST WANT TO SAY PERSONALLY I'M JUST SO GRATEFUL TO YOUR
MENTORSHIP AND YOUR LEADERSHIP FOR OUR COMMUNITY.
I WOULD I WOULD SAY PERSONALLY THAT I WOULDN'T BE HERE AND WHO
I AM AND BE ABLE TO SERVE THE COMMUNITY THE WAY I CAN SERVE
TODAY IF IT WEREN'T FOR YOUR MENTORSHIP.
>> THANK YOU MICHAEL. >> THANK YOU TO EVERYBODY FOR
SUPERVISOR CHEN FOR YOUR KIND WORDS.
>> MICHAEL, HOLD ON A SECOND. OTHER PEOPLE WANT TO SAY NICE
THINGS ABOUT YOU. >> SUPERVISOR CHEN THANK YOU,
PRESIDENT THANK YOU SO VERY SAD.
CONNIE CHEN MICHAEL ASHLEY WROTE LIKE THE SAME LONG PAGE
OF NOTES BUT I'M NOT GOING TO REPEAT MYSELF.
>> I TRULY ECHO WITH WHAT SUPERVISOR CONNIE CHEN HAS SAID
ABOUT YOU AND THE WORK. BUT I ALSO WANT TO SHARE THE
PERSONAL TOUCH THAT YOU HAVE DONE IN MY LIFE.
>> WHEN I WAS A STUDENT A HIGH SCHOOL STUDENT AT GALLIO HIGH
SCHOOL I HAD THE PRIVILEGE OF SERVING AS THE PRESIDENT FOR
THE Y C PROGRAM. >> YOU FOR CHINATOWN'S ELDERLY
PROGRAM ONE OF THE MANY IMPACTFUL INITIATIVES THAT YOU
LED AN AMERICAN AT THE AMERICAN RED CROSS AND THEIR EXPERIENCES
WAS TRANSFORM MY TAP AND THE Y C PROGRAM WE WERE TRYING TO
SERVE OUR COMMUNITY WITH A FOCUS ON DISASTER PREPAREDNESS
FOR SENIORS AND NOW FOR OUR FAMILY LIVING IN SOUTH
COMMUNITIES ESPECIALLY VULNERABLE IN A CITY LIKE SAN
FRANCISCO WHERE THE NEXT EARTHQUAKE IS NOT A QUESTION OF
IF BUT WHEN. MANY OF US AND MY PEERS AS NOW
YOU WHO YOU SHAPE AND NOW WITH THE PROGRAM IT'S BECOME
COMMUNITY LEADERS IN OUR OWN RIGHT AND AND MICHAEL YOU ARE
THE ONE WHO PLANTED ALL THE SEATS AND WE WANT TO SAY THANK
YOU FOR YOUR YOUR YOUR THANK YOU FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP AND AND
WITH THAT I ALSO, YOU KNOW ECHOED THAT YOU KNOW AND WHEN I
WAS A U I AND I TRULY APPRECIATE IT ORDER NURTURING
FROM YOU AND OTHER TEACHERS AND IT IT'S YOUR LEADERSHIP OF
CONTINUE TO LARGER GENERATION OF YOUNG LEADERS AND NOW THAT
AND MANY OF MY PEERS ARE NOW SERVING AS COMMUNITY LEADERS
AND I ALSO WANT TO ECHO THAT AND THANK YOU FOR BEING A
PUBLIC SAFETY CHAMPION FOR OUR COMMUNITIES AND CONGRATULATION
ON RECEIVING THE CIC FIRST EVER DISTINGUISHED SERVICE AWARD
AND IT'S WELL-DESERVED AND IS LONG OVERDUE AND I WANT TO
THANK YOU FOR YOUR DECADES OF SERVICE AND I ALSO WANT TO
THANK THE FAMILY HERE FOR SHARING YOU WITH US AND THANK
YOU, SUPERVISOR WALTON THANK YOU PRESIDENT MILLIMAN AND MY
CO I JUST WANT TO ADD MY VOICE TO THE COURSE.
A LOT OF TIMES WHEN PEOPLE THINK OF C, Y C THEY ONLY THINK
OF CHINATOWN. BUT YOU HAVE BEEN DOING
TREMENDOUS WORK IN BAY VIEW COMMUNITY WITH OUR NOT ONLY OUR
CHINESE FAMILIES BUT BRIDGING GAPS AND CULTURAL GAPS WITH OUR
COMMUNITY IN BAYVIEW. AND I KNOW YOU'VE BEEN DOING
THIS WORK FOR A VERY LONG TIME AND YOU TOOK THE TIME TO COME
TO COMMUNITY TO BRING COMMUNITY TOGETHER AND SO I JUST WANT TO
THANK YOU FOR YOUR WORK IN AND WITH COMMUNITY AS WELL AS FOR
YOUR MENTORSHIP OF SO MANY PEOPLE AND SOMETIMES IT CAN BE
HARD TRYING TO BRIDGE CULTURAL GAPS BUT YOU HAVE BEEN SOMEONE
WHO'S DONE AMAZING WORK AND I WANT TO MAKE SURE YOU KNOW THAT
WE APPRECIATE YOU AS WELL. >> SO THANK YOU SO MUCH.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR WALTON DISTRICT
EIGHT ALSO APPRECIATES YOU. MICHAEL.
I HAVE ENJOYED SEEING YOU AND WORKING WITH YOUR YOUTH
IN KNOWIT VALLEY AND THE MISSION AND THE CASTRO.
I KNOW THAT YOUR EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR, OUR PRESIDENT THE
ENVIRONMENT COMMISSION SARAH JUAN IS HERE ALSO TO CELEBRATE
YOU AND I WANT TO THANK SUPERVISOR CHAN FOR GIVING
GIVING A NUMBER OF US THE OPPORTUNITY TO POUR ACCOLADES
ON YOU AND NOW I THINK YOU CAN SPEAK ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU SO MUCH.
AND IT IS A GREAT HONOR TO RECEIVE THIS PROCLAMATION
AND RECOGNITION SO REFLECTS MY ALMOST 30 YEARS OF SERVICE
IN THE COMMUNITY. STOPPING FIFTH OF THE
NEIGHBORHOOD SAFETY PARTNERSHIP AMERICAN RED CROSS AND NEEDED
THE COMMUNITY YOUTH CENTER I JUST WANT TO EMPHASIZE ALL THIS
WORK WE NEED PARTNERSHIP AND SUPPORT FROM A LOT OF
PEOPLE FROM COMMUNITY PARTNERS AND IS ALSO A REFLECTION OF THE
HARD WORK OF MY COWORKERS WHO ARE HERE TODAY TO SUPPORT ME
CIC COWORKERS. >> SO I PERSONALLY WORK A LOT
WITH THE DISTRICT SUPERVISORS, THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS PAST
AND PRESENT DURING MY 30 YEARS OF WORK AND EVEN TODAY I RUN
FOR SERVICE CENTER IN BELLEVUE'S CHINATOWN,
EXCELSIOR AND RICHMOND. RIGHT.
SO I WANT TO GIVE A BIG SHOUT OUT TO SUPERVISOR SODA FOR
OVERCOMING TO LEVERAGE SOME EVENTS TO SUPPORT US.
I'VE GOT TO SUPERVISE A WARDEN FOR THE PAST EIGHT YEARS
SUPPORT TO MAKE SURE OUR SENIORS IN BAYVIEW ESPECIALLY
CHINESE SENIORS RECEIVE THE PROPER TRAINING AND SUPPORT
SUPERVISORS. >> I INTEND TO CARE ABOUT THE
SENIOR IN THE EXCELSIOR AND MAKE SURE THEY RECEIVE
TYPICAL TRAINING COMPUTER CARD STREAMING AND OTHER THINGS
AND CIVIL EQUITY IN CHIN. >> SHE ACTUALLY HELPED US OPEN
THE RICHMOND OFFICE AND BRING ALL THE SERVICES TO RICHMOND.
>> SO THANK YOU VERY MUCH. I'M SO HONEST AND I'M NOT GOING
TO I'M NOT GOING TO CONTINUE BUT WE'LL SPEND MORE TIME WITH
MY FAMILY OF COURSE AND FOR ARUN THANK YOU.
I THINK A LOT OF US YOU KNOW, YOU GOT TO GET IN OUR WHAT WAS
YOURS. >> THANK YOU.
>> OKAY. ALL RIGHT.
SUPERVISOR ALL DISTRICT TWO COLLEAGUES AND THANK YOU, MR.
PRESIDENT. >> IS ROBERT HERE?
ALL RIGHT. THERE HE THERE HE IS.
>> COLLEAGUES, TODAY I AM VERY ,VERY HONORED TO COMMEND MY
HOME NEIGHBORHOOD. >> I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU CALL
IT. PRESIDIO BRANCH LIBRARY MANAGER
ROBERT CARLSON AS HE RETIRES FOLLOWING A 14 ONE YEAR CAREER
IN LIBRARIES INCLUDING MORE THAN 30 YEARS OF SERVICE RIGHT
HERE WITH THE SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC LIBRARY.
ROBERT'S CONTRIBUTIONS HAVE NOT ONLY SEPARATED HAVE NOT ONLY
SHAPED THE PRESIDIO BRANCH LIBRARY BUT HAVE ENRICHED SAN
FRANCISCO'S LITERARY AND CULTURAL LIFE IN PROFOUND
WAYS. ROBERTS SPENT 30 YEARS WITH
THAT S.F. PL SERVING AS BRANCH MANAGER AT INGLESIDE WESTERN
ADDITION NORTH BEACH MARINA AND FOR THE PAST 11 YEARS AT
THE PRESIDIO BRANCH HE IS A TRUE LEADER WITHIN OUR PUBLIC
LIBRARY SYSTEM AND A CHAMPION OF COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT.
>> ROBERT WAS THE FIRST LIBRARIAN TO LAUNCH TECHNOLOGY
PROGRAMS AND PRESENT LIVE MUSIC INCLUDING A ROCK BAND IN BRANCH
LIBRARIES AND FOR 26 YEARS ROBERT ORGANIZED AND HOSTED SAN
FRANCISCO'S LONGEST RUNNING POETRY READING SERIES WHICH
FEATURED BOTH LOCAL AND NATIONAL POETS BORN
AND RAISED IN MANHATTAN WITH EARLY CAREER EXPERIENCE AT THE
BROOKLYN PUBLIC LIBRARY, ROBERT MOVED TO SAN FRANCISCO IN 1995
AND EVEN MORE SO HE COMES FROM A TRUE FAMILY OF LIBRARIANS HIS
WIFE TERRY IS A LIBRARIAN AT THE MAIN BRANCH AND HIS SISTER
BARBARA IS ALSO A LIBRARIAN. NOW I AM TOLD THAT YOUR FATHER
ONCE ADVISED YOU TO NOT BECOME LIBRARIANS BUT I THINK ON THE
BEHALF OF ALL SAN FRANCISCANS THANK YOU FOR NOT LISTENING.
ROBERT'S CAREER REFLECTS THE VERY BEST OF PUBLIC SERVICE,
INNOVATION, CREATIVITY AND A DEEP COMMITMENT TO COMMUNITY.
>> HE IS A COMMUNITY LEADER. HE SERVED IN LEADERSHIP ROLES
WITH THE NORTH BEACH CHAMBER OF COMMERCE, ITS BUSINESS
ASSOCIATION, THE SACRAMENTO STREET MERCHANTS ASSOCIATION
AND AS A DISASTER SERVICE WORKER HE WAS ONE OF THE CITY'S
FIRST CONTACT TRACERS DURING THE COVID 19 PANDEMIC.
YOUR VISION, YOUR LEADERSHIP, YOUR DEDICATION OF LAUGHS HAVE
LEFT A LASTING MARK ON OUR LIBRARIES AND OF THE ARTS
IN SAN FRANCISCO. SO ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD
ROBERT, THANK YOU FOR YOUR MANY, MANY CONTRIBUTIONS AND WE
WISH YOU ALL THE BEST IN RETIREMENT.
>> THE FLOOR IS YOURS. WELL THANK YOU EVERYONE.
I ESPECIALLY WANT TO THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHERYL AND THE BOARD
FOR BESTOWING THIS HONOR ON ME. IT'S I WAS VERY UNEXPECTED
AND I'M VERY GRATEFUL FOR IT. >> I BEEN VERY LUCKY TO CHOOSE
A NOBLE PROFESSION AND I'VE BEEN LUCKY TO DO WHAT I THE
KIND OF WORK I WANTED TO DO WHERE I WANTED TO DO IT
AND ALSO VERY GRATEFUL FOR THE THE POETRY COMMUNITY THAT HAS
SUPPORTED ME THROUGHOUT THE YEARS HERE.
I'VE ALSO AM VERY GRATEFUL FOR THE PEOPLE I'VE SERVED IN IN
THE DIFFERENT NEIGHBORHOODS IN THE CITY THAT I WORKED IN.
I'VE ALSO WORKED WITH SOME REALLY WONDERFUL PEOPLE OVER MY
CAREER AND AND THE WORK THAT WE DID TOGETHER AND WHAT I FEEL WE
ACCOMPLISHED. I GUESS THE BOTTOM LINE IS HAVE
YOU MADE AN IMPACT ON A COMMUNITY OR AN INDIVIDUAL?
AND IF THE ANSWER IS YES, I THINK I CAN RETIRE IN PEACE.
>> THANK YOU
ONCE YOU'VE
. >> ALL RIGHT.
MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO BACK TO A ROLL CALL.
YES. NEXT IN LINE WAS SUPERVISOR
SARTOR SUBMIT SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR CHERYL STEPPED OUT. WE'LL CIRCLE BACK TO HIM.
SUPERVISOR WALTON SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR CHAN SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR. SUPERVISOR CHEN YES.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. CALL TODAY I AM INTRODUCING A
RESOLUTION URGING GOVERNOR NEWSOM AND THE CALIFORNIA
SENATE BUDGET CHAIR TO RECOGNIZE THE IMPORTANCE OF
ACUPUNCTURE SERVICES TO MEDI-CAL PATIENTS AND COMMIT TO
FULLY RESTORING OPTIONAL ADULT ACUPUNCTURE BENEFIT IN MEDI-CAL
UPON THE PASSAGE OF CALIFORNIA STATE BUDGET.
>> WE WANT TO EMPHASIZE THE IMPORTANCE AND NECESSITY OF
RETAINING ACUPUNCTURE AS AN OPTIONAL BENEFIT UNDER MEDICAL.
>> THIS IS THE SECOND YEAR IN WHICH ACUPUNCTURE HAS BEEN
TARGETED BY THE NEWSOM ADMINISTRATION.
YET THANKS TO THE TIRELESS EFFORTS OF ELECTED OFFICIALS
AND ADVOCATES, ACUPUNCTURE WAS PRESERVED IT LAST YEAR.
IT IS CRITICAL THAT ACUPUNCTURE IS ALSO REFLECTED IN OUR
STATE'S BUDGET THIS YEAR. >> ACUPUNCTURE WAS INTRODUCED
TO AMERICAN PUBLIC OVER 50 YEARS AGO AND HAS BECOME AN
ESSENTIAL SERVICES FOR THOSE SEEKING NON PHARMACO
PHARMACOLOGICAL ALTERNATIVE FOR PAIN MANAGEMENT DEPRESSION,
OPIOID USE, THERAPEUTIC TREATMENTS AND MORE.
>> IN CALIFORNIA WE HAVE OVER 12,000 LICENSED ACUPUNCTURISTS
REPRESENTING OVER 20% AFTER AL CAPONE TOURISTS IN THAT COUNTRY
. ESPECIALLY IN THE CURRENT
POLITICAL CLIMATE WHERE AT THE FEDERAL LEVEL WE HAVE AN
ADMINISTRATION INTENT TO TAKING AWAY RIGHTS FROM OUR MOST
DISENFRANCHIZED DISENFRANCHIZED COMMUNITIES.
>> AND CUTS TO MEDICARE WILL BE DEVASTATE THAT MISSTATING
CALIFORNIA. IT'S A STATE RICH WITH
IMMIGRANTS AND COMMUNITIES THAT DEPEND ON ACUPUNCTURE AS A
NONINVASIVE TREATMENT OUTSIDE OF PHARMACOLOGICAL SOLUTIONS.
WE CANNOT REMOVE ACUPUNCTURE FROM OUR MOST VULNERABLE
COMMUNITIES STATEWIDE. THANK YOU TO THE BUDGET CHAIR
CONNIE CHEN AND OUR SUPERVISORS SALTO AND MENTOR MOEN FOR THEIR
EARLY CO-SPONSORSHIP. >> AND MADAM CLERK I HAVE
ANOTHER ONE. >> AND TODAY I'M ALSO
SUBMITTING A LETTER OF INQUIRY TO A SAN FRANCISCO PLANNING
DEPARTMENT. >> IN A FEW MONTHS THIS BOARD
OF SUPERVISORS WILL BE CALLED UPON TO VOTE ON A REZONING
PROPOSAL THAT WILL HAVE SWEEPING IMPACTS ON COMMUNITIES
ACROSS THE CITY. THIS REZONING IT'S PART OF OUR
STATE MANDATED REQUIREMENTS TO MEET OUR REGIONAL HOUSING NEEDS
ASSESSMENT OBLIGATION OWNS AND WILL CREATE ADDITIONAL
ZONING CAPACITY TO ENABLE MORE THAN 30,000 NEW HOUSING UNITS.
A SUPERVISOR I WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT WE ARE CREATING TOOLS
TO ENABLE MEMBERS OF OUR MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC TO
EXPLORE AND EVALUATE THE CHANGES THAT THE REZONING
PROPOSAL WILL HAVE IN THEIR NEIGHBORHOODS.
>> I WANT TO MAKE SURE WE ARE CREATING CONVERSATIONS ABOUT
HOW TO ACCOMMODATE NEW DEVELOPMENT IN A WAY THAT FITS
THE NEEDS, THE VULNERABILITIES AND OPPORTUNITIES IN EACH
NEIGHBORHOOD. I ALSO WANT TO ENSURE THAT WE
ARE CREATING TOOLS FOR ALL OF US AS DECISION MAKERS TO
EVALUATE HOW THE REZONING PROPOSAL HELPS US TO ADVANCE
THE GOALS THAT WE SIGNED UP FOR IN OUR HOUSING ELEMENT THINGS
SUCH AS PRESERVING RENT CONTROLLED IT HOUSING CREATING
NEW AFFORDABLE HOUSING AND PROTECTING SMALL BUSINESS.
>> AT THE APRIL 10TH HEARING OF THE PLANNING COMMISSIONS
COMMISSIONER MOORE REQUESTED THE STAFF PRODUCE A PUBLICLY
ACCESSIBLE MODELING TOOL TO ACCOMPANY THE HOUSING ELEMENT
REZONING PROGRAM. >> THIS TOOL WOULD ILLUSTRATE
THE RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN THE REZONING PROPOSALS AND KEY
INDICATORS FROM THE HOUSING ELEMENT.
>> IT WOULD ENABLE THE PUBLIC AND DECISION MAKERS TO EXPLORE
THREE DIMENSION MODELING FOR EVERY SITE AFFECTED BY THE
ZONING. >> THE TOOLS WOULD ALLOW US TO
UNDERSTAND THE IMPACT ON KEY DATA POINTS SUCH AS ORDER
AND TITLE THAT PROJECTS ON EVERY PARCEL WITH A NUMBER OF
APPROVED IT UNIT. OUR EXISTING INVENTORY OF RENT
CONTROLLED BUILDINGS AND UNITS OCCUPIED BY TENANTS HISTORIC
HISTORIC BUILDINGS OF CATEGORY A, B AND C AFFORDABLE HOUSING
OPPORTUNITY SITES AND THE DEVELOPMENT POTENTIAL AND THE
DEVELOPMENT POTENTIAL OF AFFORDABLE HOUSING UNITS.
>> PRIORITY EQUITY GEOGRAPHIES. SMALL BUSINESS INCLUDING LEGACY
BUSINESSES. >> THIS TOOLS ARE ON STEP TO
HELP THIS SORRY. >> THESE TOOLS ARE ONE STEP TO
HELP BUILD ACCOUNTABILITY TO THE GOALS THAT I BELIEVE YOU
ALL SHARE TO CREATE INCLUSIVE AND WELL-PLANNED COMMUNITIES
WHERE LOCAL COMMUNITY IS PARTNERS.
>> MY OFFICE HAS MET WITH DIRECTOR HILLIS AND WE HAVE
GIVEN HIM ADVANCE NOTICE OF THIS REQUEST IN MY LETTER OF
INQUIRY. I'M FORMALLY REQUESTING THAT
THE PLANNING DEPARTMENT PROVIDE A DETAILED OF IMPLEMENTATION
AND TIMELINE FOR WHEN AND HOW THESE TOOLS WILL MAKE AVAILABLE
FOR THE PUBLIC TO ENTER TO INTERACT WITH.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR CHEN.
SUPERVISOR CHANCE TO BE REFERRED.
>> THANK YOU. I JUST WANT TO QUICKLY COMMENT
ON AS A CO-SPONSOR TO SUPERVISOR CHEN'S LEGISLATION
URGING ABOUT THE STATE TO RECONSIDER RESCINDING COVERAGE
FOR MEDICAID FOR ACUPUNCTURE. KNOWING THAT IS A REALLY A A
PENNY WISE DOLLAR FOR DECISION BECAUSE ACUPUNCTURE CARE IS
TRULY A PREVENTIVE CARE. >> IT'S IT WILL PROVIDE PAIN
TREATMENT FOR MANY OTHER TYPES OF TREATMENTS THAT REALLY ALLOW
INDIVIDUALS TO RECEIVE PAIN RELIEF AND MANY OTHER
TREATMENTS WITHOUT GOING TO FULLY TO MEDICATION.
AND THIS TYPE OF CARE IS TRULY WHAT WE WANT TO SEE MORE OF
IN TERMS OF COVERAGE FOR ANY TYPE OF HEALTH CARE,
PARTICULARLY MEDICAID. EVEN TODAY WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
COSTS SAVING MEASURES. AND I TRULY HOPE THAT OUR STATE
AND FEDERAL GOVERNMENT REALLY BEGIN TO LOOK AT MEDICAID
AND COVERAGE IN IN HEALTH CARE IN A WAY THAT IS REALLY ABOUT
COST EFFECTIVENESS AND NOT JUST ABOUT COST CUTTING.
SO THAT IS WHAT I'M HOPING THAT WE CAN ACCOMPLISH WITH THIS
RESOLUTION IS THE SECOND TIME THAT THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN
FRANCISCO SENDING THIS MESSAGE TO OUR STATE LEGISLATURE.
I TRULY HOPE THAT THEY WILL RECONSIDER.
AND THANK YOU SO MUCH TO SUPERVISOR CHEN FOR YOUR
LEADERSHIP ON THIS AND THE REST I SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. >> SUPERVISOR CHEN SUPERVISOR
DORSEY THANK YOU MADAM CLERK. COLLEAGUES, I HAVE IN MEMORIAM
TODAY AND I'D LIKE TO ASK THAT WE ADJOURN TODAY'S MEETING
IN REMEMBRANCE OF SHARON ARDOIN ,A BELOVED FORMER MEMBER OF
SAN FRANCISCO CITY ATTORNEY'S OFFICE WHO PASSED AWAY LAST
MONTH PEACEFULLY AT HER HOME SURROUNDED BY HER FAMILY AFTER
A COURAGEOUS BATTLE WITH CANCER.
SHE WAS 76. SHARON SERVED OUR CITY FOR 26
YEARS. WHAT BEGAN AS A SIX MONTH
TEMPORARY JOB WOULD IN FACT BECOME A REMARKABLE CAREER
BEGINNING IN THE CITY ATTORNEY'S OR COUNTY ACCOUNTING
TEAM. SHE LATER JOINED THE CHILDREN
AND FAMILY TEAM UNDER LAURIE GIORGI WHO WOULD GO ON TO SERVE
AS A SAN FRANCISCO SUPERIOR COURT JUDGE.
BUT IT WAS IN HER ROLE AS THE LONGTIME FRONT OFFICE
RECEPTIONIST RIGHT HERE ON THE SECOND FLOOR OF CITY HALL WHERE
MANY OF US HAD THE CHANCE TO MEET AND GET TO KNOW SHARON
AND TO APPRECIATE WHY HER WARMTH AND WELCOMING DEMEANOR
LEFT SUCH LASTING IMPRESSIONS ON THOSE BLESSED TO KNOW HER.
SHARON WAS MORE THAN THE FACE OF THE CITY ATTORNEY'S OFFICE.
SHE WAS ITS BEATING HEART AND SHE HANDLED EVERYTHING THAT
CAME HER WAY WITH PATIENTS GRACE AND STRENGTH.
SHE BROUGHT CALM TO DIFFICULT SITUATIONS WITH KINDNESS, POISE
AND WITH A GREAT SENSE OF HUMOR.
I SPENT 14 YEARS IN THAT OFFICE WORKING WITH COLLEAGUES WHO
WOULD GO ON TO BECOME STATE AND FEDERAL JUDGES STATE
SENATOR, A STATE ATTORNEY GENERAL, GENERAL MANAGER OF A
PUBLIC UTILITY AND EVEN A VICE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES.
YET ON ANY LIST OF FORMER COLLEAGUES OF THAT OFFICE,
SHARON WOULD BE AT THE TOP OF IT.
EARLIER TODAY I WAS SPEAKING WITH FORMER CITY ATTORNEY
DENNIS HERRERA ABOUT SHARON AND HE REMINDED ME ABOUT HOW
FIERCELY PROTECTIVE SHE WAS OF ALL OF US WHO WORKED IN THE
FRONT OFFICES JUST DOWN THE HALL FROM THIS CHAMBER.
ESPECIALLY WHEN OPPOSING LITIGANTS OR LAWYERS WOULD SHOW
UP DEMANDING TO BE SEEN OR WHEN DEMONSTRATORS WOULD SHOW UP TO
TO PROTEST MARRIAGE EQUALITY OR ANY OF THE CONTENTIOUS CASES
OVER THE YEARS FOR WHICH THAT OFFICE WAS CELEBRE AIDED
AND SOMETIMES SCORNED IN NATIONAL NEWS MEDIA.
THEN I SPOKE ABOUT WHAT A STRONG AND LOYAL JOB SHE DID OF
GATEKEEPING OFTEN IN WAYS FEW OF US KNEW.
SHE WAS OUR MAMA BEAR, DENNIS SAID.
BUT WE ALL KNEW AND LOVED HER AS A SOFTIE A WARM
AND ENDEARING COLLEAGUE AND A FIERCELY LOYAL FRIEND.
AT HER RETIREMENT, SHARON SAID SHE COULD NEVER HAVE IMAGINED
WHAT STARTED AS A PART TIME CITY JOB WOULD LEAD TO WORKING
IN AN OFFICE THAT HELPED TO CHANGE THE WORLD.
BUT IT DID AND SHOW DID SHE. I AM INFORMED THAT SHARON'S
FAMILY WILL HOLD A PRIVATE CELEBRATION OF HER LIFE AND IN
HER MEMORY THEY HAVE ASKED THAT DONATIONS BE MADE TO A
CHARITABLE ORGANIZATION OF YOUR CHOICE.
ON BEHALF OF ALL WHO KNEW HER, OUR DEEPEST CONDOLENCES TO HER
FAMILY AND HER LOVED ONES. WE WILL MISS YOU, SHARON.
REST IN PEACE AND THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR DORSEY, SUPERVISOR
AND GAUDIO SUBMIT. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR FIELDER SUBMIT. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD. >> COLLEAGUES, I ASK THAT TODAY
WE ADJOURN OUR TODAY'S MEETING IN MEMORY OF CAPTAIN JULIO
DOMINIC DE LUCCI WHO PASSED ON MAY 22ND OF THIS YEAR AT THE
AGE OF 60 AFTER A COURAGEOUS 19 MONTH BATTLE WITH PANCREATIC
CANCER. >> CAPTAIN DE LUCCI WAS A
LOVING HUSBAND OF 34 YEARS TO LINDA CAPITALLY TO LUCCI AND A
FATHER TO DOMINIC AND LEAH WHOM HE LOVED BEYOND WORDS.
>> THE CAPTAIN AND HIS SON DOMINIC SHARED THE SAME PASSION
FOR HUNTING AND LOVED THEIR TRIPS TO PARADISE FARMS
TOGETHER WITH THEIR FAMILY FRIENDS.
>> JULIA WAS THRILLED TO HAVE HIS DAUGHTER BY HIS SIDE
HELPING HIM WITH HIS COMPUTER SKILLS COLLABORATING GARDEN
PROJECTS AND SUPPORTING HIM DURING HIS ILLNESS.
>> TRUE TO HIS ITALIAN HERITAGE, TIME SPENT WITH
FAMILY AND FRIENDS AND WITH FRIENDS WHO BECAME FAMILY WAS
CENTERED AROUND MEALS, LAUGHS AND CHERISHED MOMENTS THAT WILL
LIVE FOREVER WITH THOSE BLESSED ENOUGH TO HAVE TAKEN PART.
>> THE CAPTAIN WAS PROUD WAS A PROUD SAN FRANCISCO NATIVE WHO
GREW UP IN THE VISITATION VALLEY IN EXCELSIOR
NEIGHBORHOODS. HE INTENDED AND GRADUATED FROM
THE ARCHBISHOP REARDON HIGH SCHOOL IN 1982 BEFORE JOINING
THE FIRE SERVICE. THE CAPTAIN WORKED AS A FLORIST
A PROFESSION HE LOVED WITH A PASSION TALENT HE HELD CLOSE
THROUGHOUT HIS LIFE. HIS REAL PASSION, HOWEVER, WAS
BECOMING A SAN FRANCISCO FIREFIGHTER.
>> HE BRAVELY ANSWERED THE CALL TO SERVE IN 2000.
DEDICATING 25 YEARS OF HIS LIFE TO THE COMMUNITY SERVING AT
STATIONS TO NINE AND 36 AS WELL AS THE DIVISION OF TRAINING
AND FINISHING IS EXTRAORDINARILY CAREER AS A
CAPTION OF STATION 36 IN DISTRICT FIVE.
>> HE WAS PART OF THE 103RD RECRUITMENT ACADEMY OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO FIRE DEPARTMENT AND IN HIS EARLY CAREER SERVED
AS A VACATION RELIEF FIREFIGHTER IN WHICH HE HAD THE
OPPORTUNITY TO WORK AT EVERY FIREHOUSE IN THE CITY EVERY
SINGLE ONE. >> IN 2005 THE CAPTAIN BECAME
AN ENGINE DRIVER UNTIL HE WAS PROMOTED TO LIEUTENANT IN 2012
AT STATION NINE IN THE BAYVIEW .
>> JULIA WAS PROMOTED TO CAPTAIN IN 2018 OF STATION NINE
AND PROMOTED TO CAPTAIN OF IN-SERVICE TRAINING IN 2020
IN WHICH SHE TOUCHED THE LIVES OF MANY OF THE MEN AND WOMEN
WHO VALIANTLY KEEP OUR CITY SAFE.
>> HIS EMOTIONAL INTELLIGENCE, STRONG INTERPERSONAL SKILLS
AND BRILLIANT ABILITY MADE HIM AN IMPACTFUL TRAINER ONE WHO I
KNOW HAS TOUCHED THE LIVES OF MANY WHO ARE HERE TODAY.
>> IN 2022 THE CAPTAIN ACHIEVED HIS ULTIMATE CAREER GOAL OF
BECOMING THE CAPTAIN OF STATION 36.
>> CAPTAIN DE LUCCI'S LIFE WAS MARKED BY RESILIENCE,
COMPASSION AND UNWAVERING COMMITMENT TO HIS FAMILY,
COMMUNITY AND TRADITION. HIS STRENGTH IN THE FACE OF
ADVERSITY AND HIS GENEROUS SPIRIT HAVE LEFT AN INDELIBLE
MARK ON ALL WHO KNEW HIM. THE CAPTAIN'S LEGACY WILL
CONTINUE TO INSPIRE AND UPLIFT THOSE WHO ARE FORTUNATE TO HAVE
BEEN PART OF HIS LIFE. >> HIS PRESENCE WILL BE
PROFOUNDLY AND DEEPLY MISSED BEYOND WORDS BUT HIS SPIRIT
WILL LIVE ON FOREVER IN THE HEARTS OF ALL WHO KNEW HIM
AND LOVED HIM. REST IN PEACE CAPTAIN OF THE
DELIVERY. MERE MEMORY BE A BLESSING.
AND I WANTED TO THANK AGAIN THE OFFICE THE FIREFIGHTERS FROM
STATION 36 WHO ARE HERE TO COMMEMORATE HIS MEMORY AS WELL
AS CAPTAIN AND CHIEF CHRIS BROWN AS WELL.
WE'LL BE OFFERING REMARKS FROM PUBLIC COMMENT.
THANK YOU. THE REST I SUBMIT.
MADAM CLERK, DO WE DO HOW DO WE HANDLE YOU WOULD SAY ON BEHALF
OF THE ENTIRE. NO, I UNDERSTAND THAT WE'RE
GOING TO DO THIS ON BEHALF OF THE ENTIRE BOARD.
I THINK THE CHIEF WANTS TO OFFER REMARKS ON THE QUESTION
DO WE HAVE THE FLOOR? >> WITHOUT OBJECTION.
GREAT. THAT'S ALL THAT'S ALL DO THANK
YOU. PRESIDENT MANDOLIN MEMBERS OF
THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. MADAM SECRETARY, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH FOR HONORING CAPTAIN DELUCA.
HE IS NOTHING SHORT OF A LEGEND IN THIS FIRE DEPARTMENT HAD AN
INNATE ABILITY TO BE A TEACHER AND A STUDENT AT THE SAME TIME
HE TAUGHT AT OUR ACADEMY AND TOUCHED THE LIVES OF EVERY
MEMBER OF THE CROSSES PATH. IN FACT, HIS LEGACY LIVES ON
IN THE PERFORMANCE OF THESE MEMBERS TO MY LEFT AS THEY
PERFORM A CHALLENGING FUNCTION IN DISTRICT FIVE SERVICING THE
TENDERLOIN AND MISSION SOUTH OF MARKET AREAS ONE OF THE BUSIEST
ENGINE COMPANIES IN THE UNITED STATES.
IN ADDITION TO THAT THERE ARE OUR ONLY HAZARDOUS MATERIALS
UNIT IN SAN FRANCISCO RESPONDING TO UNKNOWN
EMERGENCIES HUNDREDS A YEAR AND PUTTING THEIR LIVES ON THE
LINE SO WE THANK THESE MEMBERS FOR THEIR SERVICE AS WELL AS
CAPTAIN DELUCA AND HIS FINAL ACT OF KINDNESS OFFERED ONCE HE
CONTRACTED CANCER AND SCORED HIGH ON A CHIEF'S EXAM TO GIVE
HIS PROMOTION TO THE NEXT PERSON ON THE LIST.
THAT'S PRETTY HONORABLE AND WE HONOR HIM AND CHERISH HIM.
HE WILL BE SORELY MISSED. BUT HIS LEGACY LIVES ON
IN ADDITION TO THE PERFORMANCE OF THESE MEN AND WOMEN.
BUT INTERIM AND THE REMAINDER OF THE FIRE DEPARTMENT.
SO THANK YOU ALL FOR YOUR HONOR.
WE APPRECIATE IT. >> THANK YOU, CHIEF.
THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK, FOR FINDING A WAY FOR US TO LET THE
CHIEF SPEAK DURING ROLL CALL AND WE WILL DO THAT IN MEMORIAM
FROM THE FULL BOARD. >> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
SUPERVISOR CHERYL, DID YOU HAVE ANY IDEA SORRY ABOUT THAT.
COLLEAGUES, TODAY I'D LIKE TO TALK BRIEFLY ABOUT A RESOLUTION
RECOGNIZING JUNE 6TH AS NATIONAL GUN VIOLENCE AWARENESS
DAY HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO. GUN VIOLENCE HAS TAKEN TOO MANY
LIVES, LEFT TOO MANY FAMILIES FOREVER CHANGED.
LAST YEAR NEARLY 47,000 PEOPLE IN THIS COUNTRY WERE KILLED BY
GUNS. 115,000 WERE WOUNDED.
IT IS NOW THE LEADING CAUSE OF DEATH FOR CHILDREN AND TEENS
IN THE UNITED STATES AND THIS PAIN IS NOT EVENLY SHARED.
>> YOUNG PEOPLE BLACK AND BROWN COMMUNITIES AND URBAN
NEIGHBORHOODS BEAR THE HEAVIEST BURDEN.
BUT THESE ARE NOT JUST NUMBERS. THESE ARE PEOPLE A CHILD, A
PARENT, A FRIEND WHOSE LIVES WERE STOLEN TOO SOON.
>> WE ARE HERE TODAY TO REMEMBER THEM AND TO SAY THAT
THEIR LIVES MATTERED. NATIONAL GUN VIOLENCE AWARENESS
DAY WAS CREATED TO HONOR THE LIFE OF HADIYA PENDLETON, A 15
YEAR OLD GIRL WHO WAS SHOT AND KILLED WHILE STANDING IN A
PLAYGROUND WITH HER CLASSMATES. HER FRIENDS CHOSE TO WORE
ORANGE IN HER MEMORY. THE COLOR HUNTERS WERE FOR
SAFETY AND STARTED A MOVEMENT THAT HAS REACHED ACROSS THE
COUNTRY. ON JUNE 6TH THIS FRIDAY WE'LL
WEAR ORANGE IN HONOR OF THE LIVES WE'VE LOST AND IN
SOLIDARITY WITH THOSE STILL GRIEVING AND STILL PUSHING FOR
CHANGE. >> HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO WE'VE
MADE REAL PROGRESS. LAST YEAR WE SAW THE LOWEST
NUMBER OF HOMICIDES SINCE THE 1960S AND THAT'S BECAUSE WE'VE
INVESTED IN SAFETY, IN PREVENTION, IN TRUSTED
COMMUNITY PARTNERS AND IN PUBLIC HEALTH APPROACHES TO
VIOLENCE. >> BUT THE WORK IS FAR FROM
OVER. PREVENTING GUN VIOLENCE MEANS
DOING EVERYTHING WE CAN. PASSING STRONGER LAWS
SUPPORTING SURVIVORS. REMOVING GUNS FROM DANGEROUS
SITUATIONS AND BUILDING TRUST WHERE IT'S BEEN BROKEN.
I'M GRATEFUL TO SO MANY OF MY COLLEAGUES WHO JOINED ME
IN CO-SPONSORING THIS RESOLUTION.
I WANT TO THANK MY PREDECESSOR ASSEMBLY MEMBER CATHERINE
STEPHANIE FOR HER VERY, VERY STRONG LEGACY ON THIS ISSUE.
SHE LED ON GUN SAFETY LEGISLATION HERE IN DISTRICT
TWO AND CONTINUES THAT WORK TODAY AT THE STATE.
I ALSO WANT TO THANK THE ADVOCATES, THE FRONTLINE
WORKERS AND THE FAMILIES WHO CARRY THIS FIGHT FORWARD EVERY
DAY. YOUR COURAGE, YOUR FIERCE
COMMITMENT TO THIS WORK ARE AN INSPIRATION.
I HAVE PROFOUND ADMIRATION FOR THE WAY YOU TURN YOUR GRIEF
INTO POWER TO INSPIRE LASTING CHANGE.
>> SAN FRANCISCO STANDS WITH YOU.
WE WON'T LOOK AWAY AND WE WON'T GIVE UP.
>> SECOND TODAY I'M INTRODUCING A RESOLUTION URGING THE SAN
FRANCISCO POLICE DEPARTMENT AND THE DEPARTMENT OF EMERGENCY
MANAGEMENT TO CLASSIFY ALL 911 CALLS REGARDING ILLICIT DRUG
ACTIVITY WITHIN 1500 FEET OF PARKS, PLAYGROUNDS AND SCHOOLS
AS PRIORITY A EMERGENCIES. >> THESE AREAS ARE WHERE OUR
COMMUNITY, CHILDREN AND FAMILIES GATHER AND THEY
DESERVE THE HIGHEST LEVEL OF SAFETY.
THIS RESOLUTION CALLS FOR IMMEDIATE RESPONSE TO SAFEGUARD
PUBLIC SAFETY AND SEND A CLEAR MESSAGE WE WILL NOT TOLERATE
OPEN DRUG ACTIVITY IN PUBLIC SPACES WHERE OUR CHILDREN PLAY
AND LEARN. PARENTS SHOULD NOT HAVE TO
THINK TWICE ABOUT TAKING THEIR KIDS TO THE PARK.
>> FAMILIES SHOULD NOT HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT WALKING TO SCHOOL.
A CHILD'S SAFETY SHOULD NEVER BE PUT ON HOLD.
IF WE'RE SERIOUS ABOUT PROTECTING CHILDREN WE NEED TO
RESPOND WITH URGENCY WHEN THEIR SAFETY IS AT RISK.
WE HEAR FROM FAMILIES ACROSS THE CITY WHO ARE TRYING TO
RAISE THEIR KIDS IN SAN FRANCISCO THAT TOO OFTEN BASIC
SAFETY FEELS LIKE AN AFTERTHOUGHT.
>> THIS RESOLUTION IS ABOUT BEING CLEAR THAT THE SAFETY OF
CHILDREN AND THE LIVABILITY OF OUR NEIGHBORHOODS IS NOT
NEGOTIABLE. WHEN A PARENT CALLS FOR HELP,
THE CITY NEEDS TO SHOW UP QUICKLY AND CONSISTENTLY
BECAUSE OUR CHILDREN DESERVE TO GROW UP IN NEIGHBORHOODS THAT
FEEL SAFE AND CARED FOR. THAT STARTS WITH SHOWING UP
WHEN FAMILIES CALL FOR HELP. THIS IS ABOUT MAKING OUR CITY'S
PRIORITIES CLEAR AND PUTTING THEM INTO ACTION.
>> FINALLY, I'D LIKE TO ADJOURN TODAY'S MEETING IN MEMORY OF
WILLIAM JOSEPH HEEP, A BELOVED DISTRICT TWO COMMUNITY MEMBER
AND A COMMITTED VOLUNTEER FOR THE LAFAYETTE PARK CONSERVATION
PROGRAM. BILL WAS A LOVING, FUNNY,
CULTURED, SENSITIVE, KIND AND LOYAL BROTHER UNCLE
AND FRIEND. HE WAS A MAN OF INTEGRITY
AND HONESTY WHO SADLY PASSED AWAY ON FEBRUARY 23RD OF THIS
YEAR. HE IS SURVIVED BY HIS SIBLINGS
,HIS NIECES AND NEPHEWS AND MANY, MANY CLOSE PERSONAL
FRIENDS MANY OF WHOM REMAIN ACTIVE IN THE LAFAYETTE PARK
COMMUNITY. BUT BEYOND HIS ROLE IN THE
CONSERVATION PROGRAM, BILL WAS AN AVID READER, GARDENER
AND PRESENCE IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
KNOWN FOR A KINDHEARTED, GENEROUS SPIRIT AND IN
APPRECIATION OF A REALLY GOOD BOTTLE OF WINE.
I WANT TO EXTEND MY CONDOLENCES TO HIS FRIENDS AND TO HIS
FAMILY FOR THEIR LOSS AND I LOOK FORWARD TO JOINING THE
LAFAYETTE PARK COMMUNITY THIS SATURDAY TO MEMORIALIZE BILL
AND HONOR HIS MANY CONTRIBUTIONS TO THE PARK
AND OUR CITY. >> THE REST I SUBMIT THANK YOU
SUPERVISORS. >> SHERYL.
MR. PRESIDENT, SEEING NO OTHER NAMES ON THE ROSTER THAT
CONCLUDES THE INTRODUCTION OF NEW BUSINESS.
>> RIGHT. LET'S GO TO PUBLIC COMMENT AT
THIS TIME THE BOARD WELCOMES YOUR PUBLIC COMMENT IF YOU LINE
UP ON YOUR RIGHT HAND SIDE OF THE CHAMBER NEAR THE CURTAINS
YOU MAY SPEAK TO THE APPROVAL OF THE BOARD MEETING MINUTES AS
PRESENTED THE. >> FOR ADOPTION WITHOUT A
COMMITTEE REFERENCE ITEMS 31 AND 32 ALL OTHER ITEMS THAT
HAVE BEEN REPORTED OUT BY THE BOARD BY AN APPROPRIATE
COMMITTEE ARE NOT ELIGIBLE TO BE SPOKEN ABOUT BUT YOU CAN
SPEAK TO GENERAL MATTERS. WE'RE SETTING THE TIMER FOR TWO
MINUTES. WELCOME CHRIS.
AS FOR SPEAKER TODAY GOOD AFTERNOON BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
PRESIDENT FOR THE RECORD MY NAME IS CHRIS WARD KLEIN.
I ALSO GO BY SERGEANT KLEIN OF THE UNITED STATES MARINE CORPS
ACTIVE DUTY. YESTERDAY I SPOKE AT THE HEALTH
COMMISSION. ITEM FIVE I WOULD SUGGEST THAT
YOUR TEAMS GO BACK AND LISTEN TO THAT PUBLIC COMMENT ON ITEM
FIVE. BASICALLY THE BUDGET THE CITY
IS ELIGIBLE TO GET 5 BILLION PLUS DOLLARS FROM THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT WITH UNCLAIMED DAMAGES AND THE CITY ATTORNEY'S
OFFICE DOESN'T WANT TO SUBMIT THIS BECAUSE THERE'S PEOPLE
NAMED IN AN INDICTMENT FROM SAN FRANCISCO.
AND THAT'S REALLY GOING TO HURT SAN FRANCISCO BECAUSE WE NEED
THAT MONEY. AND AGAIN, I WOULD STRONGLY
SUGGEST THAT YOU GET WITH THE MAYOR GREG WAGNER AND MAYBE
JESSE SMITH BRING HIM BACK AS THE INTERIM CITY ATTORNEY
AND REWORK THE BUDGET WITH THE $5 BILLION.
GLYDE NEEDS THAT MONEY. SALVATION ARMY NEEDS THAT
MONEY. EVERYBODY NEEDS THAT MONEY
AND WE CANNOT LAY OFF 1500 PEOPLE THAT WOULD SET US INTO A
DEPRESSION WHICH WOULD BE A DOMINO EFFECT ACROSS THE CITY,
ACROSS THE STATE AND ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
THE ISSUE IS THAT PEOPLE. SEVERAL THEN IT WENT TO A DOZEN
THEN IT WENT TO 2 OR 3 DOZENS. WE GET A HOLD OF CREDENTIALS
AND THEN THEY TO GO FIND A CORPORATION OR A UNIVERSITY OR
A DIFFERENT STATE OR A DIFFERENT COUNTRY TO GIVE THEM
ACCESS WITH THAT ACCESS THEY ALLOWED OTHER PEOPLE THIRD
PARTY COUNTRIES TO COME IN WITH THEIR SURVEILLANCE SYSTEMS THE
CYBER STALK PEOPLE. THAT SAID UNFAVORABLE THINGS TO
THE PRESIDENT TO THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS, TO THE MAYOR THAT
WAS CAUSING YOUR MENTAL HEALTH CRISIS, THAT WAS CAUSING YOUR
OVERDOSES. THIS IS COMING OUT I'M WORKING
WITH THE COMMERCE DEPARTMENT, THE DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE
AND THE MARINE CORPS THIS IS COMING OUT FOR REFERENCE.
YOU CAN GO BACK AND GOOGLE AUDRA.
WHEN THE UNIVERSITIES WERE DOING THE EXACT SAME THING
AND IT GOT VERY UGLY HERE IN THE UNITED STATES.
THANK YOU. HAVE A GOOD DAY.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> LET'S WELCOME OUR NEXT
SPEAKER. >> YOU'RE BOTH COMING UP TO THE
PODIUM. YOU'LL EACH HAVE YOUR OWN TWO
MINUTES. >> I CAN.
>> MY APOLOGIES IN ADVANCE. MY COMMENTS TODAY ARE NOT
RELATED TO THE AGENDA PREVIOUSLY SPOKEN OF.
FIRST OFF, AS I WALKED INTO THE BUILDING AT THE SECURITY CHECK
AND I NOTICED THAT THERE WAS A HAT WITH JINGLING BELLS AND RED
SQUEAKY NOSE PERHAPS THE MAN WHO WAS ESCORTED.
FROM THE PREMISES EARLIER TODAY COULD BE CONNECTED WITH HIS
BELONGINGS. I HOPE THE SHERIFF'S DEPARTMENT
CAN HELP WITH THAT. MY NAME IS JOHN PAUL UP
AND JANI. I'M A PARTNER AT SUTRO POWER, A
LOCAL SOLAR AND BATTERY INSTALLATION FIRM AND I'M HERE
TO MAKE A PLEA ON BEHALF OF OUR LOCAL INDUSTRY.
IN 2018 THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS COMMITTED TO
AMBITIOUS GOALS FOR CLEAN ENERGY AND SAN FRANCISCO
SPECIFIC ONLY A 100% RENEWABLE ELECTRICITY BY 2030 AND NET
ZERO EMISSIONS BY 2040. I STAND BEFORE YOU TODAY TO SAY
THAT SAN FRANCISCO IS BACKSLIDING ON THOSE
COMMITMENTS. >> THIS HAS NOTHING TO DO WITH
THE POTENTIAL ERASURE OF THE 30% TAX CREDIT AT THE FEDERAL
LEVEL NOR WITH CALIFORNIA'S RECENT SLASHING OF SOLAR
COMPENSATION RATES. THE PROBLEM IS OUR OWN CITIES
PERMITTING PROCESSES AND HOW IT HAS BEEN DRAMATICALLY ALTERED
IN THE PAST TEN MONTHS. SAN FRANCISCO HAS SLID QUITE A
BIT FROM BEING ONE OF THE MOST SENSIBLE AND EXPEDIENT
JURISDICTIONS TO DO SOLAR AND BATTERY IN THE NATION.
PROPERTY OWNERS AND RENTERS LIVING IN CONDOS AND APARTMENTS
WITH MORE THAN TWO UNITS ARE THE MOST IMPACTED WITH A
POSSIBLE LOSS OF THE TAX CREDIT THIS YEAR WE MAY HAVE TO STOP
TAKING ON THESE PROJECTS ENTIRELY DUE TO THE PERMITTING
HURDLES. I WANT TO BE CLEAR THIS IS NOT
MY INTENTION TO CRITICIZE ANY CITY WORKER OR DEPARTMENT.
>> THE PROBLEM IS STRUCTURAL AND TOP DOWN THERE IS NO
CENTRALIZED CLEAR FRAMEWORK GUIDING HOW THESE PERMANENT
RULES ARE PROPOSED, REVIEWED OR IMPLEMENTED AND INPUT FROM OUR
LOCAL INDUSTRY HAS BEEN TOTALLY EXCLUDED.
I URGE THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS TO INVESTIGATE THE CURRENT
STATE OF SOLAR AND BATTERY PERMITTING IN SAN FRANCISCO.
CONSULT WITH S.F. BASED COMPANIES AS WELL AS ESTABLISH
PROFESSIONALS IN THE FIELD. >> WORK WITH US TO CRAFT A
COHERENT AND THANK YOU SIR. THE TIMES CONCLUDED THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER
. >> HELLO MY NAME IS FAITH
SANCHEZ. >> I LIVE IN DISTRICT EIGHT
AND I WORK IN THE TENDERLOIN NEIGHBORHOOD OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> I AM HERE WITH CLYDE CENTER FOR SOCIAL JUSTICE.
PLEASE DO NOT CUT FUNDING FOR SODA TAX FUNDED PROGRAMS
INCLUDING BLIND SOCIAL JUSTICE ACADEMY.
THIS PROGRAM IS AN ESSENTIAL TENDERLOIN SPACE FOR ENSURING
THAT MARGINALIZED COMMUNITIES HAVE A VOICE AND RESOLVING THE
HEALTH ISSUES THAT IMPACT THEM SUPPORTING COMMUNITY LEADERS
AND DEVELOPING SOLUTIONS TO HEALTH INEQUITIES IN THEIR OWN
LANGUAGES AND THEIR OWN COMMUNITIES.
AND THEN ADVOCATING FOR AND SHARING THEIR FINDINGS WITH
THEIR COMMUNITIES IS A CRUCIAL PART OF ADDRESSING FOOD
INSECURITY NEEDS. >> REVENUE FROM THE SOURCES
FROM THE SODA TAX ARE SUPPOSED TO SUPPORT COMMUNITY DRIVEN
PROGRAMS LIKE GLIDE SOCIAL JUSTICE ACADEMY AND OTHER
INNOVATIVE. COMMUNITY LED WORK TO DECREASE
THE CONSUMPTION OF STRAWBERRY BEVERAGES AND SUPPORT HEALTHY
EATING AND ACTIVE LIVING. PROMOTION OF HEALTHY EATING
LEADS TO BETTER QUALITY OF LIFE OUTCOMES BY REDUCING CHRONIC
HEALTH DISPARITIES AMONG COMMUNITIES OF COLOR.
>> THE SOCIAL JUSTICE ACADEMY IS A SUPPORTIVE ENVIRONMENT FOR
COMMUNITY MEMBERS TO PROCESS AND HEAL FROM THE IMPACTS OF
SYSTEMIC RACISM AND HEALTH INEQUITIES.
PLEASE CONTINUE THE ESSENTIAL FUNDING FOR SODA TAX GRANTS SO
GLIDE CAN RUN OUR SOCIAL JUSTICE ACADEMY AND FISCAL YEAR
2025 2026. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
THANK YOU SUPERVISORS MY NAME IS JUSTIN, A SAN FRANCISCO
RESIDENT AND A MEMBER OF THE MISSION ATHLETIC CLUB A PURELY
VOLUNTEER LED TENNIS COMMUNITY THAT'S GROWN ALMOST 2000
MEMBERS THROUGH. FREE PUBLIC COURTS HERE IN SAN
FRANCISCO. I'M URGING YA'LL TO VOTE NO ON
THE $5 AN HOUR TENNIS COURT RESERVATION FOR THIS FEE GOES
DIRECTLY AGAINST PARKS AND REC PHILOSOPHY OF PRESERVING AN
ENVIRONMENT FOR THE WELL-BEING OF EVERYONE IN OUR DIVERSE
COMMUNITY AND IS DOUBLE DIPPING INTO OUR TAX DOLLARS.
OUR PUBLIC COURTS HAVE BEEN AN INCREDIBLE.
THIRD SPACE FOR MYSELF I COULD HAVE NEVER IMAGINED IT WOULD
LEAD ME DOWN A PATH THAT WOULD CONNECT ME WITH SUCH GREAT
COMMUNITY AND STRENGTHEN MY LOCAL TIES AFTER LOSING MY JOB
THIS PAST YEAR I PICKED UP TENNIS AS AN OUTLET FOR ME TO
STAY HEALTHY AND SANE AND NAVIGATE MY CAREER OPTIONS.
MONEY WAS TYPE. THANKFULLY THE COURTS WERE
FREE. I FOUND MYSELF PLAYING 4 TO 5
TIMES A WEEK. A $5 FEE WOULD EQUATE TO ABOUT
700 TO $1100 PER YEAR A COST THAT WOULDN'T HAVE BEEN ABLE TO
AFFORD NOR COULD SAN FRANCISCO YOUTH OR LOW INCOME PLAYERS
IN OUR COMMUNITIES. THIS FEE WAS PRIMARILY BACKED
BY PARKS AND RECS ALLIANCE, A GROUP WHO JUST MISUSED $3.8
MILLION IN RESTRICTED FUNDS THIS PAST YEAR AND ARE NOW
SHUTTING DOWN AND WITHOUT AN AUDIT HOW CAN WE TRUST THAT THE
BACKING FOR THESE FEES WOULD BE IN GOOD FAITH FOR THIS MEASURE
? THERE ARE BETTER SOLUTIONS
WITHOUT FINANCIAL BARRIERS SUCH AS NO SHOW PENALTIES.
COMMUNITY PARTNERSHIPS I WATCH THIS CHAMBER ADMIRE THE GRACE
AND LEADERSHIP OF A LOT OF OTHERS THIS AFTERNOON
AND RESPECTFULLY I ASK THAT YOU GIVE ME AND MY COMMUNITY THAT
SAME FEELING TOWARD YOURSELVES BY VOTING NOW AND NOT STIFLING
WHAT WE'VE ALL BUILT TOGETHER SO LET'S KEEP OUR PUBLIC SPACES
FREE AND ALLOW COMMUNITY AND CIVIC WELLNESS TO FLOURISH
IN OUR NEIGHBORHOODS. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> LET'S HEAR FROM OUR NEXT
SPEAKER. WELCOME.
>> HELLO DEAR SUPERVISORS, MY NAME IS ELAINA.
I AM ALSO A PROUD MEMBER OF THE MISSION ATHLETICS CLUB.
I URGE YOU TO VOTE NO ON THE PROPOSED $5 COURT RESERVATION
FEE. THIS POLICY WOULD BURDEN THE
VERY COMMUNITIES THESE COURTS ARE MEANT TO SERVE WHILE
OFFERING LITTLE FINANCIAL BENEFIT AND CREATING MAJOR
LOGISTICAL CHALLENGES. >> FREE PUBLIC COURTS HAVE BEEN
A VITAL PART OF REBUILDING MY COMMUNITY AFTER AFTER RETURNING
TO US FROM SEATTLE, THE SENSE OF BELONGING CAME FROM OPEN
ACCESS NOT A PAYWALL $5 AN HOUR FEE WOULD EQUATE TO ABOUT AS MY
PREVIOUS CALLER MENTIONED 1100 A YEAR WHICH IS UNAFFORDABLE
FOR MANY ESPECIALLY IN A CITY WHERE 100,000 IS CONSIDERED LOW
INCOME. PARKS AND REC HAS SHARED NO
SOLID DATA TO JUSTIFY THIS FEE .
>> THIS PROPOSAL IS BACKED BY GROUPS UNDER FINANCIAL SCRUTINY
RISKS SETTING PRECEDENT FOR FUTURE PRICE HIKES AND REDUCED
PARTICIPATION. THERE ARE BETTER SOLUTIONS SO
PLEASE VOTE NO TO KEEP OUR COURTS FREE, PUBLIC
AND ACCESSIBLE FOR ALL. THANK YOU FOR YOUR
CONSIDERATION. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER. >> HELLO SUPERVISORS.
IT'S NICE TO SEE YOU ALL. MY NAME IS IAN JAMES.
I AM THE COMMUNITY ENGAGEMENT MANAGER AT GLIDE CENTER FOR
SOCIAL JUSTICE. I AM ALSO HERE TO TALK ABOUT
THE FUNDING FOR A DEEP. SUGARY DRINK DISTRIBUTOR TAX OR
SODA TAX FUNDED PROGRAMS WHICH HAVE BEEN CUT IN THE CURRENT
DRAFT OF THE BUDGET. >> SOME OF YOU WILL REMEMBER
THAT WE WERE HERE LAST YEAR WHEN THIS FUNDING WAS ALSO CUT.
COMMUNITY BASED ORGANIZATIONS CAME FROM ACROSS SAN FRANCISCO
D FIVE D TEN D 11 TO CITY HALL TO SHARE STORIES OF HOW THIS
MONEY SUPPORTS LOCAL FARMS GETS FOOD TO HUNGRY FAMILIES,
NURTURES NEW COMMUNITY HEALTH WORKERS AND SUPPORTS EMERGING
LEADERS AND ADVOCATES. COMMUNITY MEMBERS MADE THE TREK
TO SHARE THROUGH PUBLIC COMMENT HOW THESE PROGRAMS HAVE CHANGED
THEIR LIVES AND ONE YEAR LATER THAT WORK IS STILL HAPPENING
AND IS STILL VITAL. >> AND I'M REALLY DEVASTATED
THAT WE ARE BACK HERE AGAIN FIGHTING FOR THEIR SURVIVAL
IN THE TENDERLOIN GLIDE AND DC WERE AWARDED FUNDING TO
CONTINUE OUR SOCIAL JUSTICE ACADEMY.
AND FOOD POLICY COUNCIL RESPECTIVELY.
THESE ARE ESSENTIAL TO UNDERLYING SPACES FOR ENSURING
THAT MARGINALIZED COMMUNITIES HAVE A VOICE IN RESOLVING THE
HEALTH ISSUES THAT DISPROPORTIONATELY IMPACT THEM.
AND CLYDE SPECIFICALLY WAS PLANNING ON USING THESE FUNDS
TO SUPPORT BLACK COMMUNITIES IN ADDRESSING FOOD INSECURITY.
CHRONIC HEALTH INEQUITIES THROUGH COMMUNITY BUILDING,
RESEARCH, EDUCATION AND ADVOCACY FIRSTHAND I HAVE
SEEN IN PROGRAMS LIKE THIS ONE AND THE PROGRAMS FUNDED BY THE
SODA TAX RELIEF CONNECTION HEALING BONDS FORM ACROSS
DIFFERENCES. THE COURAGE TO CONFRONT TRAUMA
AND THE EMERGENCE OF TRANSFORMATIONAL LEADERSHIP.
THESE OUTCOMES ARE REAL AND THEY ARE CRUCIAL IF SAN
FRANCISCO IS ACTUALLY COMMITTED TO TRULY HEALTHY COMMUNITIES
BEYOND SIMPLY MANAGING THE MOST VISIBLE SYMPTOMS OF INEQUITY.
SO PLEASE SUPERVISORS AS YOU CRAFT THE FINAL VERSION OF OUR
CITY'S BUDGET INCLUDE THE ESSENTIAL FUNDING FOR SODA TAX
GRANTS SO PROGRAMS LIKE OURS CAN CONTINUE TO EXIST.
THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER. >> GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS.
I'M HAPPY TO HAVE THE OPPORTUNITY TO SPEAK WITH ALL
OF YOU AT ONCE. MY NAME IS APPLE KRONK.
I AM A MEMBER OF THIS COHORT FOR GLIDE SOCIAL JUSTICE
ACADEMY AND I WANT TO SHARE WITH YOU THAT I AM PROFOUNDLY
SAD TO HEAR THAT THIS PROGRAM IS ON THE CHOPPING BLOCK FOR AT
LEAST THE NEXT FEW YEARS. I WANT TO TELL YOU A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT WHAT THIS PROGRAM HAS DONE FOR ME.
>> PLEADING THAT YOU'LL RECONSIDER.
I HAVE A BEEN A RESIDENT OF SAN FRANCISCO FOR OVER 19 YEARS.
MUCH OF THAT TIME I SPENT LIVING ON THE STREETS
STRUGGLING TO SURVIVE AND USING SUBSTANCES TO COPE WITH
PSYCHOLOGICAL TRAUMA OF MY PAST AND THE DESTITUTE BROKENNESS OF
MY PRESENT. LIVING IN THE SHADOWS OF THIS
COMMUNITY AND MAKING MY HOME WITHIN THE CRACKED CONCRETE
CONCRETE MARGINS OF THIS BEAUTIFUL THRIVING COMMUNITY OF
ART, CULTURE AND WEALTH I FELT ALL BUT INVISIBLE YET BEFORE
YOU HERE I STAND IN ACTIVIST AND ADVOCATE A MOTHER OF A
BEAUTIFUL TWO YEAR OLD MIRACLE HERE AND NOW BEFORE YOU CLEAN.
NOT MERELY ON THE SURFACE OR BY.
THE BLOOD IN MY VEINS BUT IN MY SOUL.
I'VE BEEN SOBER FOR OVER TWO YEARS NOW RENT AN APARTMENT
IN DISTRICT SEVEN WITH MY PARTNER AND DAUGHTER.
IT WAS IT WAS THANKS TO SOME OF MANY INCREDIBLE PROGRAMS THAT
EXIST HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO THAT I SURVIVED AND MADE IT
HERE TO THIS. STAGE OF MY RECOVERY.
BUT I WOULDN'T EVEN BE SHARING ANY OF THIS WITH YOU IF IT WERE
NOT FOR THE SOCIAL JUSTICE ACADEMY HELPING ME TO FIND MY
VOICE AND GIVING ME A SENSE OF VALUE FOR THE UNIQUE
EXPERIENCES THAT I'VE HAD. SOCIAL JUSTICE ACADEMY HELPED
ME FIGURE OUT HOW TO SHARE MY STORY TO INFORM POLICYMAKERS
LIKE YOURSELVES HOW TO BETTER SERVE THE PEOPLE OF THIS
COMMUNITY WHO CONTEND WITH SIMILAR HARDSHIPS AS I HAD.
>> SO AS WE FIGHT FOR POSITIVE CHANGES WE MUST DEFEND
AND UPLIFT THE INCREDIBLE PROGRAMS LIKE THIS WHICH GIVE
FOLKS LIKE ME THE OPPORTUNITY TO FIND THEIR VOICE, FIND THEIR
NICHE AND MAKE PROFOUND CHANGES IN THEIR COMMUNITY.
>> THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
LET'S WELCOME OUR NEXT SPEAKER .
>> GOOD AFTERNOON ESTEEMED BOARD OF SUPERVISORS LEADERS.
>> MY NAME IS LINDA MANTELL AND I AM A MEMBER OF THE GLIDE
COMMUNITY CHURCH, THE GLIDE MEMORIAL CHURCH AND I'VE BEEN
LIVING AND WORKING IN THE TENDERLOIN FOR NEARLY 50 YEARS
. I'M A 35 YEAR MEMBER OF THE
GLIDE FAMILY AND A CURRENT MEMBER OF THE GLIDE CHURCH
BOARD AND ALONG WITH MY COLLEAGUES I WOULD URGE YOU NOT
TO CUT THE FUNDING FOR THE SODA TAX FUNDED PROGRAM.
THE GLIDE CENTER FOR SOCIAL JUSTICE AS YOU WERE JUST TOLD,
IS AN ESSENTIAL PROGRAM FOR OUR COMMUNITY.
AND SO I WOULD ASK YOU SIMPLY NOT TO CUT THE FUNDS THAT WOULD
ALLOW US TO CONTINUE THAT PROGRAM.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER. >> GOOD AFTERNOON ESTEEMED
BOARD. MY NAME IS TOBY SACHS QUINTANA.
I'M A RESIDENT OF SAN FRANCISCO AND DISTRICT EIGHT AND A MEMBER
OF THE MISSION ATHLETIC CLUB THAT GREW ALMOST ENTIRELY OUT
OF FREE ACCESS TO OUR PUBLIC COURTS.
>> I URGE YOU TO VOTE NO ON THE $5 FEE THAT WILL GO ON TO THE
COURTS. BECAUSE WE'LL IMPACT THOSE THAT
THAT NEED IT MOST WORKING FAMILIES, SENIORS, STUDENTS,
THOSE AFFECTED BY LAYOFFS DUE TO ECONOMIC UNCERTAINTY AND AND
THOSE AFFECTED BY RECENT LAYOFFS IN TECH AND THE MISSION
ATHLETIC CLUB HAS GIVEN ME A REAL THIRD SPACE TO MEET PEOPLE
THAT I WOULD NOT HAVE MET OTHERWISE AND TO BUILD
COMMUNITY. I FEEL LIKE ATHLETICS
AND SPORTS IS A WAY THAT TRANSCENDS BOUNDARIES LIKE VERY
FEW THINGS CAN AND I FEEL LIKE BECAUSE OF THE MISSION ATHLETIC
CLUB AND OUR FREE COURTS I HAVE MY PLACE IN THE BEAUTIFUL
MOSAIC THAT IS SAN FRANCISCO AND NOW TO THE FEE REX AND PARK
HAVE PREDICATED THIS FEE ON NO SHOWS WE ARE YET TO SEE THE
DATA ON THOSE SHOWS. IT'S ALSO BACKED THIS FEE BY
THE PARKS ALLIANCE WHICH WAS RECENTLY EXPOSED FOR MISUSING
MILLIONS OF FUNDS. >> I'D LIKE TO THANK SUPERVISOR
FIELDER FOR PROPOSING AN AUDIT TO SAN FRANCISCO REC AND PARKS
AND I THINK WE REALLY NEED TO SEE WHAT TURNS OUT IN THAT
AUDIT ON REX AND PARKS AND THEIR CONNECTION WITH THE
PARKS ALLIANCE. >> WE ALSO NEED BROADER
COMMUNITY INPUT AND THERE ARE BETTER SOLUTIONS SUCH AS
CORPORATE SPONSORSHIPS, PRIVATE LESSON FEES AND OTHER WAYS TO
GENERATE REVENUE WITHOUT PUNISHING EVERYDAY PLAYERS.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER .
HELLO SUPERVISORS. MY NAME IS MAY AND I'M A SAN
FRANCISCO RESIDENT AND ALSO A MEMBER OF THE MISSION ATHLETIC
CLUB HERE TO ASK YOU TO VOTE NO ON THE PROPOSED $5 TENNIS COURT
RESERVATION FEE PUBLIC ACCESS MATTERS DEEPLY TO ME.
>> I ONLY STARTED PLAYING TENNIS BECAUSE IT WAS FREE IF
THERE HAD BEEN A FEE EVEN JUST FIVE DOLLARS I WOULD HAVE NEVER
PICKED UP A RACKET LIKE MANY PEOPLE I DIDN'T GROW UP PLAYING
. I DIDN'T HAVE THE GEAR.
I CERTAINLY DIDN'T THINK OF TENNIS AS ACCESSIBLE BUT FREE
PUBLIC COURTS AND FREE TENNIS PROGRAMS PUT ON BY COMMUNITIES
LIKE THE MISSION ATHLETIC CLUB CHANGE THAT THEY GAVE ME A WAY
TO MOVE TO CONNECT WITH OTHERS AND TO FEEL PART OF THE CITY.
>> I FEEL A VITALIZED AND A SENSE OF BELONGING TO SAN
FRANCISCO BECAUSE OF THE COMMUNITY I'VE BUILT THANKS TO
THE FREE PUBLIC PARK ACCESS A $5 FEE MIGHT SEEM SMALL BUT IT
CREATES A REAL BARRIER FOR BEGINNERS STUDENTS AND ANYONE
UNSURE IF THEY BELONG ON A COURT.
IT TELLS PEOPLE THIS SPACE ISN'T FOR YOU UNLESS YOU
ALREADY PLAY UNLESS YOU HAVE THE MONEY AND THAT GOES AGAINST
WHAT PUBLIC PARKS SHOULD STAND FOR OPENNESS, EQUITY
AND COMMUNITY. >> WE DON'T NEED TO CHARGE THE
PUBLIC TO PRESERVE OUR PARKS. >> THERE ARE BETTER WAYS TO
MANAGE ACCESS WITHOUT SHUTTING PEOPLE OUT.
PLEASE PROTECT THE SPIRIT OF PUBLIC PLAY AND VOTE NO ON THIS
FEE. >> THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
>> HELLO SUPERVISORS. MY NAME IS ARGIN.
I'M A SAN FRANCISCO RESIDENT AND MEMBER OF THE MISSION
ATHLETIC CLUB. AND I ALSO URGE YOU TO VOTE NO
ON THE $5 PER HOUR COURT RESERVATION FEE.
>> THIS FEE BURDENS THE WRONG PEOPLE GENERATE A LITTLE BIT
JUST SO IT GENERATES A LITTLE REVENUE AND IS OPERATIONALLY
FLAWED. >> SO THE TENNIS COURTS HAVE
SERVED AS A WAY FOR ME TO CONNECT WITH THE ROOTS OF MY
COMMUNITY AND STRENGTHEN LOCAL TIMES LOCAL TIES.
>> I FEEL LIKE A REAL SAN FRANCISCAN WHEN LIKE I WENT TO
A LOCAL RESTAURANT POST HATING AND ASKED ME DO YOU WANT TO GET
THE USUAL? OR THE ART GALLERY OWNER NEXT
DOOR RECOGNIZE ME WALKING BY WITH MY TENNIS GEAR AND JACKET.
AND THAT SENSE OF BELONGING COMES FROM HAVING ACCESS TO
THESE FREE COURTS. AND AS OTHER PEOPLE HAVE
MENTIONED, THIS IDEA WAS PRIMARILY BACKED BY THE S.F.
PARKS ALLIANCE AND S.F. TENNIS COALITION AND AS YOU KNOW, THEY
MISUSED ALMOST $4 MILLION IN RESTRICTED FUNDS LAST YEAR.
AND AS A POTENTIAL YESTERDAY WE'LL BE SHUTTING DOWN SHORTLY.
AND RECENTLY SUPERVISOR FIELDER CALLED FOR AN AUDIT ON THE RECS
SAME PARK AS WELL. SO I DON'T KNOW HOW WE CAN
TRUST THE BACKING OF THESE FEES WAS MADE WITH GOOD FAITH WHEN
ALL OF THESE THINGS ARE COLLAPSING BEHIND THEM.
AND THIS $5 FEE EQUALS AROUND 800 TO ALMOST $1,200 A YEAR FOR
REGULARS AND IS UNAFFORDABLE FOR MANY YOUTH, SENIORS AND LOW
INCOME RESIDENTS. 100,000 IS CONSIDERED LOW
INCOME IN SAN FRANCISCO AND RECS AND PARKS HAVE OFFERED
ONLY ANECDOTES ABOUT REVENUE NO SHOWS IN UTILIZATION AND HASN'T
PRESENTED ANY SOLID DATA. I BELIEVE THIS FEE WOULD REDUCE
OR REDUCE USAGE AT SATELLITE COURTS AND PAVE THE WAY FOR
PRICE CREEP AS WE'VE SEEN AT THE GOLDMAN TENNIS CENTER.
AND MONITORING WEATHER AND ENFORCING THESE FEES WOULD
BE VERY COSTLY AND COMPLEX. SO YEAH, PLEASE I URGE YOU TO
VOTE NO AND THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS .
>> LET'S HEAR FROM OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
GOOD AFTERNOON EVERYONE. MY NAME IS DR. DINA ABDO
AND I'M A SAN FRANCISCO RESIDENT, A PEDIATRICIAN
AND ALSO A PROUD MEMBER OF THE MISSION ATHLETIC CLUB WHICH AS
YOU ALL HAVE HEARD IS A VOLUNTEER LED TENNIS COMMUNITY
THAT GREW ENTIRELY THROUGH FREE PUBLIC COURT ACCESS.
AND I AM ALSO HERE TO URGE YOU TO VOTE NO ON THE PROPOSED $5
COURT RESERVATION AND FEE I JOINED THE MISSION ATHLETIC
CLUB DURING ONE OF THE MOST INTENSE AND EXHAUSTING PERIODS
OF MY MEDICAL RESIDENCY TRAINING PROGRAM.
THE ABILITY TO WALK ONTO A FREE PUBLIC COURT NO SIGN UP, NO
COST FELT LIKE A LIFELINE TO ME.
TENNIS BECAME MY OUTLET FOR MANAGING STRESS, STAYING
PHYSICALLY ACTIVE AND MOST IMPORTANTLY BUILDING GENUINE
FRIENDSHIPS OUTSIDE THE HOSPITAL.
>> THE EXPERIENCE HAS PROFOUNDLY IMPROVED BOTH MY
PHYSICAL AND SOCIAL WELL-BEING. AND I KNOW I'M NOT ALONE
IN THAT. AS A PHYSICIAN I SEE FIRSTHAND
HOW ESSENTIAL PHYSICAL ACTIVITY IS TO IMPROVING MENTAL
AND PHYSICAL HEALTH. >> TENNIS IS A LIFELONG SPORT
THAT BUILDS COORDINATION, IMPROVES CARDIOVASCULAR
FITNESS, REDUCES ANXIETY, FOSTERS CONFIDENCE
AND CONNECTION, MAKING IT LESS ACCESSIBLE THROUGH IMPOSING A
COURT FEE WOULD BE A DIRECT BLOW TO THE PUBLIC HEALTH OF
OUR COMMUNITY IN SAN FRANCISCO. >> THERE ARE BETTER, MORE
EQUITABLE SOLUTIONS THAT DON'T IMPOSE FINANCIAL BARRIERS SO
PLEASE VOTE NO ON THIS FEE. HELP US PROTECT PUBLIC ACCESS
AND PROTECT THE COMMUNITIES LIKE THE MISSION ATHLETIC CLUB
THAT ARE HELPING SAN FRANCISCO NOT JUST PLAY BUT HEAL.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> LET'S WELCOME OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
>> HI SUPERVISORS. MY NAME IS BELINDA HONG.
I'VE BEEN A RESIDENT OF SAN FRANCISCO FOR EIGHT YEARS
AND FOR THE PAST YEAR HAVE BEEN A MEMBER OF THE MISSION
ATHLETIC CLUB. AND TODAY I'M HERE TO URGE YOU
TO HELP PROTECT OUR COURTS AND KEEP ACCESS FOR YOU.
IN MY TIME IN SAN FRANCISCO I'VE HAD THE PRIVILEGE OF
CIRCULATING MANY DIFFERENT CIRCLES BETWEEN TECH ART
AND NIGHTLIFE AND I CAN SAY THAT THIS COMMUNITY IS A LIVING
EXAMPLE OF WHAT HAPPENS WHEN WE PRIORITIZE EQUITY ACCESS,
COMMUNITY ATHLETICS AND NON TRANSACTIONAL STEWARTS
STEWARDSHIP IN A CITY THAT HAS SEEN SO MUCH CHANGE
AND TRANSIENTS IN A SHORT AMOUNT OF TIME.
WHAT I FOUND ON THE TENNIS COURT WAS MAGICAL.
PEOPLE FROM EVERY NEIGHBORHOOD, EVERY BACKGROUND COMING
TOGETHER AROUND SHARED COURTS AND SHARED VALUES.
>> NO MEMBERSHIP FEES, NO BARRIERS JUST NEIGHBORS HELPING
NEIGHBORS LEARN PLAY AND BELONG.
>> THIS IS WHAT INCLUSIVITY LOOKS LIKE IN ACTION NOT
BECAUSE ANYONE MANDATED IT BUT BECAUSE FREE ACCESS NATURALLY
CREATES IT. >> THE COMMUNITY STEWARDSHIP
I'VE EXPERIENCED IS EXTRAORDINARY.
PEOPLE VOLUNTEER THEIR TIME SHARE EQUIPMENT, ORGANIZE
EVENTS ALL WITHOUT ANY FINANCIAL TRANSACTION REQUIRED
. AND THIS IS CIVIC ENGAGEMENT AT
ITS PUREST RESIDENTS CARING FOR EACH OTHER AND OUR SHARED
PUBLIC SPACES FOR FREE COURTS DON'T JUST PROVIDE RECREATION
THEY PROVIDE CONNECTION MENTAL HEALTH AND BELONGING.
THEY CREATE THE THIRD SPACES OUR NEIGHBORHOODS DESPERATELY
NEED ESPECIALLY AS OUR CITY FACES CHALLENGES WITH ISOLATION
AND COMMUNITY FRAGMENTATION. >> A $5 HOURLY FEE UP TO 1001
70 ANNUALLY FOR REGULAR PLAYERS WOULD FUNDAMENTALLY CHANGE THIS
DYNAMIC. >> IT WOULD EXCLUDE THE VERY
PEOPLE WHO NEED COMMUNITY CONNECTION THE MOST.
>> SO WE'RE NOT JUST TALKING ABOUT TENNIS COURTS.
WE'RE IN PUBLIC SPACES. OUR FREE MAGIC HAPPENS.
AUTHENTIC COMMUNITY CAN FLOURISH WHERE SAN FRANCISCO'S
PROMISE OF OPPORTUNITY AND BELONGING REMAINS
ACCESSIBLE TO ALL. >> PEOPLE SHOW UP AS THEY ARE,
CONTRIBUTE WHAT THEY CAN AND BUILD AUTHENTIC
RELATIONSHIPS WITHOUT FINANCIAL BARRIERS.
AND THIS IS CIVIC WELLNESS. >> IT'S BASED.
I URGE YOU TO VOTE NO ON THIS FEE AND THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
HELLO SUPERVISORS. MY NAME IS JASON PRADO AND A
RESIDENT OF THE MISSION DISTRICT.
I'M ALSO A MEMBER OF THE MISSION ATHLETIC CLUB, A
VOLUNTEER TENNIS COMMUNITY THAT HAS GROWN ENTIRELY THROUGH FEE
FREE PUBLIC TENNIS COURT ACCESS.
I ALSO URGE YOU TO VOTE NO ON THE PROPOSED $5 COURT
RESERVATION FEE. SINCE I STARTED PLAYING TENNIS
THREE YEARS AGO, THE PARKS HAVE BECOME AN EVEN MORE IMPORTANT
PART OF MY LIFE. THE COURTS ARE A PLACE I GO TO
SEE FRIENDS, MAKE NEW FRIENDS AND TO STAY HEALTHY.
WHAT I LIKE MOST ABOUT OUR PARKS THOUGH IS THAT FOR THE
COUPLE OF HOURS I'M THERE I'M NOT A CUSTOMER, I'M NOT A WAGE
EARNER. I'M NOT ENGAGED IN A COMMERCIAL
TRANSACTION. I'M THERE AS A CITIZEN AND A
MEMBER OF A COMMUNITY. THAT IS ONLY POSSIBLE BECAUSE
THE PARK IS FREE. ONCE YOU PAY FOR SOMETHING
YOU'RE A CUSTOMER AGAIN. I DON'T WANT TO BE A CUSTOMER
EVERY MINUTE OF MY LIFE. FOR ME WHAT STARTED AS A GROUP
CHAT FOR SOME UNDEREMPLOYED FRIENDS TO PLAY PICK UP MATCHES
AFTER THE PANDEMIC HAS GROWN TO A THOUSAND MEMBERS AND A REALLY
BIG GROUP CHAT WHERE PEOPLE FIND COMMUNITY AND FIND A LOVE
FOR OUR CITY. THE MISSION ATHLETIC CLUB IS A
PLACE PEOPLE FIND BELONGING AND SAN FRANCISCO.
THERE'S THIS IDEA THAT YOUNG PEOPLE MOVE TO S.F. JUST TO
ADVANCE THEIR CAREERS BUT THEY SEE THE CITY AS A TRANSACTION.
I DON'T FEEL THAT WAY. I'VE BEEN HERE ALMOST 20 YEARS
AND I SEE PEOPLE ON THE TENNIS COURT GET INVESTED IN SAN
FRANCISCO TOO. THEY FALL IN LOVE WITH IT
AND THEY GIVE BACK TO IT AND THAT MATTERS.
I'M CERTAIN THAT IF WE HAD TO BE CUSTOMERS TO PLAY TENNIS ON
OUR BEAUTIFUL COURTS THAT COMMUNAL FEELING WILL DISAPPEAR
. THE COURSE WILL HAVE A PRICE
BUT MUCH LESS VALUE AND OUR COMMUNITY WILL BE POORER FOR
IT. PROTECT OUR COURTS.
PLEASE SAY NO TO THE $5 FEE. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
NEXT SPEAKER WELCOME. HI EVERYONE.
I'M PRINCE BOUCHER, A RESIDENT OF DISTRICT NINE AND FOUNDER OF
THE MISSION ATHLETIC CLUB. WE BELIEVE COMMUNITY ATHLETICS
IS A VEHICLE FOR CIVIC WELLNESS.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN? WE HOST ABOUT 25 EVENTS A MONTH
ON TOP OF SEVERAL PROGRAMS AND WE ALSO HOST THAT SERVICE
OUR 2000 MEMBER COMMUNITY. BASICALLY MEMBERS USED TO PLAY
2 TO 3 TIMES A MONTH AND NOW THE PLAY TWO TIMES 2 TO 3 TIMES
A WEEK. ALL OF THIS IS FREE BUT FOR
SOME REASON THERE'S A CONSPIRACY WITHIN PD THAT WE
ARE A FOR PROFIT ORGANIZATION. FOR THE RECORD WE ARE NOT.
THEY CAN ALL ATTEST TO THIS AS WELL AS THE REST OF THE
COMMUNITY. I'M ALSO HERE TO SAY NO TO THE
$5 FEE. JUST WANT TO REITERATE THAT WE
HAD OVER 3000 PEOPLE WHO SIGNED A PETITION.
I'M SURE A LOT OF YOU GOT OUR EMAILS AS WELL.
AND THEN I ALSO WANT TO SAY THAT THERE'S SOMETHING TO LEARN
ABOUT WHAT WE'RE DOING HERE AS A FREE SERVICE AND THIS IDEA OF
STEWARDSHIP FOR PD. I BELIEVE WE'RE DOING A LOT OF
THEIR WORK AND URBAN UTILIZATION, SOCIAL WELL-BEING,
PHYSICAL HEALTH, URBAN ACTIVATION AND ECONOMIC
DEVELOPMENT. THE GAME WE PLAY IT'S CALLED
LIVE BALL. WE BASICALLY GET 24 PEOPLE ON
THE COURT ON TO COURT SORRY WHICH THIS COURT UTILIZATION
IDEA OF THE $5 FEE WOULD HELP INCREASE THE CAPACITY.
WE'RE DOING THAT JOB VERY WELL. ON CERTAIN DAYS WE GET 50
PEOPLE ON THREE COURTS. THAT WOULD BE 22 COURTS TAKEN.
WE DO THAT WITH THREE COURTS. IF WE WERE ENABLED WE'D BE ABLE
TO DO A LOT MORE. WE'VE ONLY BEEN AROUND FOR 18
MONTHS AND THIS IS CERTAINLY SOMETHING THAT'S KEPT ME IN THE
CITY. AND THE REASON I LOVE STAYING
IN SAN FRANCISCO WE DEFINITELY BELIEVE THAT WE DELIVER MORE
GDP THAN THIS TRIVIAL $300,000 THAT IF FEW WOULD CONTRIBUTE
TO. IT'S ALSO HIGHLY GROSSLY
STATED. AGAIN, THIS FEE WILL REDUCE THE
HIGH VALUE DRIVING COMMUNITY THAT'S DOING ITS PART TO
REVITALIZE SAN FRANCISCO. PLEASE DO NOT PASS THIS $5 FEE.
THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
MIKE SPEAKER, WELCOME. >> OH, HELLO.
>> I WAS BORN ON A MILITARY BASE RAISED ON MILITARY BASES
AND BY A PATRIOTS WHO WAS IN CHARGE OF AMERICA'S WEAPONS
USED TO TERRORIZE INNOCENT PEOPLE WORLDWIDE.
I NOW CONDEMN NATIONALISM IN AMERICA'S WAR CRIMES AGAINST
HUMANITY NATIONALLY AND INTERNATIONALLY.
IN THAT VEIN, I CONDEMN AMERICA'S TERRORIZING
AND EXECUTION OF JONATHAN JOSS WHO IS A COMANCHE AND WHITE
MOUNTAIN APACHE. THIS IS A STATEMENT FROM
KRISTIN, HIS HUSBAND. MY HUSBAND AND I WERE INVOLVED
IN A SHOOTING WHILE CHECKING THE MAIL AT THE SITE OF OUR
FORMER HOME THAT HOME WAS BURNED DOWN AFTER OVER TWO
YEARS OF THREATS FROM PEOPLE IN THE AREA WHO REPEATEDLY TOLD
US THEY WOULD SET FIRE TO IT. WE REPORTED THESE THREATS TO
LAW ENFORCEMENT MULTIPLE TIMES AND NOTHING WAS DONE THROUGHOUT
THAT TIME. WE WERE HARASSED REGULARLY BY
INDIVIDUALS WHO MADE IT CLEAR THEY DID NOT ACCEPT OUR
RELATIONSHIP. MUCH OF THE HARASSMENT WAS
OPENLY HOMOPHOBIC. WHEN WE RETURNED TO THE SITES
TO CHECK OUR MAIL WE DISCOVERED THE SKULL OF ONE OF OUR DOGS
AND ITS HARNESS PLACED IN CLEAR VIEW.
THIS CAUSED BOTH OF US SEVERE EMOTIONAL DISTRESS.
WE BEGAN YELLING AND CRYING IN RESPONSE TO THE PAIN OF WHAT
WE SAW WHILE WE WERE DOING THIS A MAN APPROACHED US.
HE YELLED, STARTED YELLING VIOLENCE, HOMOPHOBIC SLURS AT
US AND HE RAISED HIS GUN FROM HIS LAP AND FIRED JONATHAN
AND I HAD NO WEAPONS. WE WERE NOT THREATENING ANYONE.
WE WERE GRIEVING. WE WERE STANDING SIDE BY SIDE
WHEN THE MAN FIRED, JONATHAN PUSHED ME OUT OF THE WAY.
HE SAVED MY LIFE. JONATHAN IS MY HUSBAND.
HE GAVE ME MORE LOVE IN OUR LIFETIME OUR LIFE TOGETHER THAN
MOST PEOPLE EVER GETS. WE WERE NEWLYWEDS.
WE PICKED VALENTINE'S DAY. WE WERE IN THE PROCESS OF
LOOKING FOR A TRAILER AND PLANNING OUR FUTURE.
HE WAS MURDERED BY SOMEONE WHO COULD NOT STAND THE SIGHT OF
TWO MEN LOVING EACH OTHER. I WAS WITH HIM WHEN HE PASSED.
I TOLD HIM HOW MUCH HE WAS LOVED TO EVERYONE WHO SUPPORTED
HIM HIS FANS, HIS FRIENDS KNOW THAT HE VALUED YOU DEEPLY.
HE SAW YOU AS FAMILY AND MY FOCUS NOW IS ON PROTECTING
JONATHAN'S LEGACY AND HONORING THE LIFE WE BUILT TOGETHER.
>> IF YOUR CONCERN IS HOW SOMEONE COPED WITH TRAUMA OR
HOW LOUDLY THEY SPEAK WHEN RECOUNTING INJUSTICE AND BEING
IGNORED BY AUTHORITIES THEN YOU NEVER TRULY CARED ABOUT MY
HUSBAND JONATHAN SAVED MY LIFE. I WILL CARRY THAT FORWARD.
I WILL PROTECT WHAT HE BUILT. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER. >> HELLO SUPERVISORS.
MY NAME IS CHRISTOPHER MAGUIRE AND I'M BORN AND RAISED HERE
IN THE CITY. I'M INVOLVED IN A NUMBER OF
ORGANIZATIONS SUCH AS GOING TO QUATTRO SFO, LDC AND I'M HERE
TO SUPPORT SUPERVISOR WALDEN'S RESOLUTION OPPOSING STATE CUTS
TO MEDICARE FOR UNDOCUMENTED ADULTS.
AS A FIRST GENERATION AMERICAN, I OWE MY ENTIRE LIFE TO MY
PARENTS WHO IMMIGRATED HERE TO THE UNITED STATES FROM HONDURAS
. >> THEIR HARDSHIPS AND BATTLES
IN NAVIGATING THIS COUNTRY HAVE SET UP A LIFE FOR ME AND MY
FAMILY. RIGHT NOW, HOWEVER, OUR
COMMUNITIES ARE BEING TARGETED FROM THE CONSTANT THREAT OF ICE
RATES TO NOW GUTTED FUNDS. IT FEELS LIKE WE ARE FIGHTING
AN UPHILL BATTLE. >> HEALTH CARE IS ALREADY SUCH
A COMPLEX THING TO UNDERSTAND AND THESE KINDS OF CUTS ONLY
CREATE MORE BARRIERS FOR OUR UNDOCUMENTED FAMILIES.
>> AFTER SEEING THIS RESOLUTION, I AM HOPEFUL THAT
WE WILL CONTINUE TO MOVE FORWARD AND CREATE MORE
EQUITABLE DECISIONS IN POLICY. I WANT TO ONCE AGAIN SAY THANK
YOU TO SUPERVISOR WALTON AND THE CO-SPONSORS OF THIS
RESOLUTION FOR TAKING A STAND AND FIGHTING FOR WHAT'S RIGHT.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
>> YES, THANK YOU ALL. IT'S NICE TO TALK TO YOU ALL
IN ONE ROOM. THIS I THINK IS MY FIRST PUBLIC
COMMENT. SO GREAT TO SEE YOU ALL.
I ALSO WANT TO CONCUR WITH A COUPLE OF PEOPLE THAT SPOKE
ABOUT GUN VIOLENCE PREVENTION AS WELL AS THE $5 FEE FOR THE
TENNIS COURTS. I'M OBVIOUSLY A PERSON THAT
ADVOCATES FOR A GREAT LOCAL GOVERNMENT WHO PROVIDES GREAT
SERVICES AND OBVIOUSLY TO PROVIDE THOSE SERVICES YOU NEED
FUNDS. BUT I THINK IT'S ALSO IMPORTANT
FOR LOW INCOME RESIDENTS TO HAVE ACCESSIBILITY TO THOSE
COURTS. >> SO I WANT TO URGE A NO VOTE
ON THAT. >> BUT THE REASON I WANTED TO
TALK TO YOU GUYS TODAY IS FOR THE NATIONAL GUN VIOLENCE
AWARENESS MONTH OR SORRY DAY. I THINK IT'S REALLY IMPORTANT
FOR US TO RECOGNIZE THAT DAY BECAUSE YOU KNOW, I'M A YOUNG
PERSON AND A LOT OF OUR YOUNG PEOPLE ARE FEARFUL OF GOING TO
SCHOOL OF GOING TO UNIVERSITY BECAUSE THEY'RE FEARFUL THAT
SOMEONE WILL COME IN WITH A GUN AND HONESTLY OUR SCHOOL SHOULD
NOT BE A UNIVERSITY ZONE OR SORRY, YOU KNOW, LIKE A
MILITARY ZONE WHERE WE HAVE TO HAVE POLICE AROUND IN THE WHOLE
PLACE TO KEEP OUR CHILDREN SAFE.
AND WE SHOULDN'T HAVE TO HAVE OUR CHILDREN GO THROUGH DRILLS
,YOU KNOW. >> SO I OF COURSE SUPPORT THE
SECOND AMENDMENT. BUT UNFORTUNATELY THERE'S BEEN
A LOT OF THINGS ROLLED BACK IN THE STATE OF CALIFORNIA
RECENTLY AND REGARDING THE THE USE OF GUNS IN PUBLIC.
SO I THINK THIS IS A GREAT FIRST STEP FOR OUR CITY TO
RECOGNIZE THAT WE SUPPORT THE SECOND AMENDMENT.
OF COURSE THIS IS THE UNITED STATES BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY WE
SUPPORT PEOPLE'S SAFETY AND PEOPLE'S OUR CHILDREN'S
SAFETY. SO THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHERYL
FOR BRINGING THAT UP. >> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. LET'S WELCOME OUR NEXT SPEAKER
. >> GOOD AFTERNOON, PRESIDENT
MERRIMAN. BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
MY NAME IS MICHAEL RUPAK. I AM A DISTRICT NINE RESIDENT.
I'M ALSO THE VICE PRESIDENT FOR POLITICAL AFFAIRS FOR LATIN X
DEMOCRATIC CLUB IN SAN FRANCISCO.
>> I'M HERE TODAY TO ASK FOR A COURSE OF ACTION.
I'M HERE TO ASK THAT YOU SWIFTLY AND IMMEDIATELY PASS A
RESOLUTION THAT FORMALLY OPPOSES GOVERNOR NEWSOM'S
PROPOSED MEDICARE CUTS AND ENROLLMENT FREEZE.
THESE THESE CUTS WILL HURT OUR COMMUNITIES.
WE NEED AN AFFIRMED COMMITMENT TO TO HAVE THE SECURITY
AND HAVE THE LEADERSHIP IN SAN FRANCISCO PUSH BACK WHEN WE ARE
BEING ATTACKED FEDERALLY. AND NOW AT THE STATE LEVEL WE
NEED OUR CITY TO COME IN AND SUPPORT OUR COMMUNITIES.
SO PLEASE RISE TO THIS CALL OF ACTION.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH. HAVE A GREAT DAY.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. ALL RIGHT.
THIS MIGHT BE OUR LAST SPEAKER IF YOU'RE HERE TO PROVIDE
GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT. PLEASE STEP UP TO THE LINE
OTHERWISE THIS WILL BE OUR LAST SPEAKER.
WELCOME, SIR. MY NAME IS RICHARD RUSTY
PETERSON AND I'M HERE TO TALK ABOUT COMMUNICATIONS
AND PARTICULARLY COMMUNICATIONS WITH SOME OF OUR MOST NOTABLE
CITIZENS SUCH AS SIR JONATHAN IVES.
I NOTICED IN A RECENT NEWSPAPER ARTICLE WHICH I I'M SURE YOU
HAVE ALL SEEN I GUESS DOES THAT SHOW UP OR DO I HAVE TO SLIDE
IT SOMEWHERE? >> YES, WE CAN SEE IT.
WELL I'M SURE I'M SURE EVERYBODY IN THIS ROOM IS LEFT
IN THIS ROOM AS I READ IT. BUT IN ANY EVENT, THE OPEN
AND TRANSPARENT COMMUNICATIONS WITH SIR JONATHAN IVE AND OTHER
NOTABLES CITIZENS SUCH AS MARC BENIOFF IS REALLY AN ALLUSION.
>> AND IF YOU TRY AND MAKE A DIRECT COMMUNICATION WITH THEM
THEY DUCK AND DODGE. I ONLY BRING THIS UP BECAUSE
IN THE FUTURE YOU CAN'T REALLY TRUST THESE LARGE COMPANIES.
I'VE BEEN IN THE BUSINESS OF INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY
LITIGATION FOR 20 YEARS OH MAYBE 50 YEARS NOW I'M GETTING
OLD AND I REALLY THINK THAT THE NEXT THING THAT IS COMING DOWN
THAT YOU MUST BE YOU AS A BOARD MUST BE REALLY CAREFUL OF IS A
PUSH FOR PARCEL TAXES THAT GO BEYOND THE LITTLE PARCEL TAX
THAT WE NOW SUFFER ON RESIDENCES BECAUSE MANY OF
THESE CORPORATIONS ARE LARGE ON A SINGLE PARCEL.
AND THAT IS THE EASIEST WAY TO STEAL THE TAXPAYERS MONEY.
OAKLAND IS DOING IT IN GREAT SHAPE WITH MANY DIFFERENT ONES
. >> SO I THANK YOU FOR ALLOWING
ME TO SPEAK. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> SEEING NO OTHER SPEAKERS, MR. PRESIDENT.
>> ALL RIGHT. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSED. LET'S GO TO OUR FOR ADOPTION OF
THAT COMMITTEE REFERENCE AGENDA ITEMS 31 AND 32 ITEMS 31
THROUGH 32 WERE INTRODUCED FOR ADOPTION BUT WITHOUT REFERENCE
TO COMMITTEE. A UNANIMOUS VOTE IS REQUIRED
FOR ADOPTION OF A RESOLUTION ON FIRST READING TODAY.
ALTERNATELY ALTERNATIVELY A MEMBER MAY REQUIRE A RESOLUTION
ON FIRST READING TO GO TO COMMITTEE.
>> DOES ANYONE WANT TO SEVER ANY ITEMS?
I DON'T SEE ANYONE SO ON ON THE ADOPTION COMMITTEE REFERENCE
AGENDA MADAM CLERK CAN YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEMS
31 AND 32. >> SUPERVISOR MANDEL MAN HI.
MANDEL MAN I'M SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR
SADR I SUPERVISOR FOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON
WALTON I SUPERVISE HER CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN
EYES SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR ENGARDIO
AND ENGARDIO I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I
AND SUPERVISOR MA'AM WHAT MY MODE I THERE ARE 11 EYES ALL
RIGHT WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK DO WE HAVE ANY IMPERATIVE AGENDA ITEMS THERE
AN UNDER REPORT MR. PRESIDENT, COULD YOU PLEASE READ THE
IN MEMORIAM? TODAY'S MEETING WILL BE
ADJOURNED IN MEMORY OF THE FOLLOWING BELOVED INDIVIDUALS
ON BEHALF OF PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN FOR MR. STEVE
KELLERMAN ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR CHERYL FOR THE LATE
MR. WILLIAM JOSEPH HEEP ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR DORSEY FOR
THE LATE MS. SHARON ARDOIN AT THE REQUEST AND ON BEHALF OF
SUPERVISOR OF MY MOOD AND PRESIDENT MANDEL MEN A
MOTION HAS BEEN MADE ON BEHALF OF THE ENTIRE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS FOR THE LATE CAPTAIN JULIO DOMINIC DELUCA.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. I THINK THAT BRINGS US TO THE
END OF OUR AGENDA. DO WE HAVE ANY FURTHER BUSINESS
BEFORE US TODAY? >> THAT CONCLUDES OUR BUSINESS
FOR TODAY. >> THEN WE ARE ADJOURNED